<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An act for granting a supply to His Majesty, by raising money by way of a poll</title>
            <author>Ireland.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1697</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 97 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 36 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A45968</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing I304</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R39282</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">18320706</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 18320706</idno>
            <idno type="VID">107354</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A45968)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 107354)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1636:18)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An act for granting a supply to His Majesty, by raising money by way of a poll</title>
                  <author>Ireland.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>58 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Andrew Crook ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCXCVII [1697]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Poll tax --  Ireland.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  History --  1691-</term>
               <term>Ireland --  Politics and government --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:107354:1"/>
            <p>AN ACT FOR Granting a Supply TO HIS MAJESTY, BY Raiſing Money by way of a POLL.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>D<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>BLIN:</hi> Printed by <hi>Andrew Crook,</hi> Printer to the King's Moſt Excellent Majeſty, on <hi>Cork-Hill,</hi> near <hi>Copper-Alley.</hi> MDCXCVII.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="Act">
            <pb facs="tcp:107354:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:107354:2"/>
            <head>An ACT for Granting a ſupply to His Majeſty, by rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing Money by way of a POLL. CHAP. XXXIII.</head>
            <p>WE Your Majeſty's moſt Dutiful and Loyal Subjects, the Commons of <hi>IRELAD</hi> in Parliament Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled, having a grateful ſenſe of the Benefits we enjoy under the Auſpicious Reign of our great Deliverer and Defender, with all Thankfulneſs and Humility, own Your Majeſty's Goodneſs to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards us, and Your Indefatigable Pains and Care for our Safety: And taking into our Conſideration, that many Debts Contracted by Your Majeſty for our Security and Preſervation, remain unpaid, through a Deficiency of Your Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty's Eſtabliſhed and Settled Revenue to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge the ſame. As a further Acknowledgment of the Sincerity and Loyalty of our Hearts, Do moſt humbly Preſent Your Majeſty a Freé Gift of the ſeveral Summs hereafter following, to be Levyed in manner herein-after expreſſed; for, and towards the payment and diſcharge of the Debts and other Ends hereafter particularly mentioned: And do veſeéch Your Majeſty to accept thereof, And that it may be Enacted,</p>
            <p>And be it Enacted by the King's moſt Excellent Majeſty, by, and with the Advice and Conſent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:107354:3"/>in this preſent Parliament Aſſembled, and by the Authority of the ſame, That all and every perſon and perſons of what Age, Sex, or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greé ſoever, that ſhall be in this Kingdom at the time of executing this Act, ſhall pay unto His Majeſty Two ſhillings, <hi>ſterl. per ann.</hi> To commence from the Sixth day of <hi>November,</hi> in the Year of Our Lord God. One thouſand Six hundred Ninety ſeaven, except the Wives and Daughters of Day-Labourers, living with their Parents, and the Sons of Day-Labourers who have not attained their Age of Eighteén Years; and alſo except Widows, who by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of their poverty, are diſcharged from pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Hearth-money, and all perſons living on Alms.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That all and every perſon and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, who at the time of the execution of this Act, ſhall be of the ſeveral Qualities, Ranks, Orders and Degreés hereafter mentioned, ſhall Annually pay unto His Majeſty the ſeveral Summs hereafter in this Act ſet down and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, beſide, and over and above their ſaid Annual Poll of Two ſhillings, <hi>ſterl.</hi> (That is to ſay) Every Arch-Biſhop of this Kingdom, ſhall pay the Summ of Fifty pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Biſhop of this Kingdom, ſhall pay the Summ of Twenty pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every Dean of this Kingdom, ſhall pay the Summ of Ten pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every Arch-Deacon of this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, ſhall pay the Summ of Five pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every Cannon, or Prebendary of this Kingdom ſhall ſeverally pay the Summ of Fifty ſhillings, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every Doctor of Divinity, Law, or Phi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſick, ſhall pay the Summ of Five pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:107354:4"/>Every Perſon having two or more Benefices, with Eure of Souls, making together One hundred pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> or upwards, ſhall pay Five pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every perſon having one Bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, with Cure of Souls, of the Yearly Value of One hundred pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> ſhall pay Threé pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every perſon having one or more Benefice or Benefices, with Cure of Souls, of the Yearly Value of Fifty pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> and under a hundred pounds, Yearly Value, ſhall pay the ſumm of One pound, <hi>ſterl.</hi> and no more. Every perſon having a <hi>Sine</hi> Cure, or Benefice, without Cure of Souls, of the Yearly Value of One hundred pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> ſhall pay the ſumm of Ten pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> and ſo after the Rate proportionably for any greater or leſſer <hi>Sine</hi> Cure, or Benefice without Cure of Souls, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing under or above the Yearly Value of One hundred pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every Parſon or Incum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bent, having but one Benefice with Cure of Souls, and not reſiding thereon, or having more Benefices then one, with Cure of Souls, and not reſiding on any one of them, ſhall pay for every ſuch Benefice of the Yearly Value of One hundred pounds, <hi>ſter.</hi> the ſumm of Ten pounds, <hi>ſter.</hi> and after that Rate proportionably for every greater or leſſer Benefice. And every Parſon, or Vicar, having any Benefice or Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefices, with Cure of Souls, under the Year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Value of Fifty pounds <hi>ſter.</hi> ſhall pay the ſumm of Ten ſhillings. Every Chancellor of a Dioceſs, or Vicar-General, ſhall pay Five pounds <hi>ſter.</hi> Every Regiſter of a Dioceſs, ſhall pay the ſumm of Two pounds ten ſhillings <hi>ſter.</hi> E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Chancellor of a Cathedral, ſhall pay two pound ten ſhillings, <hi>ſter.</hi> Every Dignitary, of
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:107354:5"/>what nature or kind ſoever, ſhall pay Two pounds ten ſhillings, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every Curate having no Benefice, ſhall pay Ten ſhillings, and no more.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That every perſon and perſons, who at the time of the execution of this Act, ſhall be of the ſeveral Ranks and Degreés hereaf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter mentioned, and ſhall be then within this Kingdom, or that hath any Eſtate in Lands, Tenements, or Hereditaments in the ſame, ſhall pay unto His Majeſty the ſeveral Summs of Money hereafter in this Act ſet down and appointed. (That is to ſay) Every perſon of the Degreé of a Duke, of this Kingdom, ſhall pay the ſumm of Fifty pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every perſon of the Degreé of a Marqueſs, having any Eſtate in this Kingdom, ſhall pay Forty pounds. Every perſon of the Degreé of an Earl, inhabiting, or reſideing in this Kingdom at the time of the execution of this Act, or having any Eſtate in the ſame, ſhall pay the ſumm of Thirty pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every perſon of the Degreé of a Viſcount, that ſhall be in this Kingdom at the time of the execution of this Act, or that hath any Eſtate in the ſame, ſhall pay the ſumm of Twenty five pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> And that every perſon being of the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greé of a Baron, of this Kingdom, who ſhall be in the ſame at the time of the execution of this Act, or that hath any Eſtate in this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, ſhall pay the ſumm of Twenty pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> And that every perſon being eldeſt Son of ſuch Duke, who is Charged Fifty pounds, as aforeſaid, ſhall pay Thirty pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every younger Son of ſuch Duke, ſo Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:107354:5"/>as aforeſaid, ſhall pay the ſumm of Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty five pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every eldeſt Son of ſuch Marqueſs, as is before Charged, ſhall pay the ſumm of Twenty five pounds. Every young<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er Son of ſuch Marqueſs, ſhall pay the ſumm of Twenty pounds, <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every eldeſt Son of ſuch Earl, as is before Charged with Thirty pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> ſhall pay the ſumm of Twenty pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every younger ſon of ſuch Earl as is Charged as aforeſaid, the ſumm of Fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teén pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every eldeſt ſon of ſuch Viſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count, Charged by this Act with the payment of Twenty five pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> ſhall pay the ſumm of Seaventeén pounds ten ſhillings <hi>ſterl.</hi> Eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry younger ſon of ſuch Viſcount, ſo Charged as aforeſaid, ſhall pay the ſumm of Thirteén pounds ſix ſhillings and eight pence. Every eldeſt ſon of ſuch Baron, as is before Charged by this Act with the payment of the ſumm of Twenty pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> ſhall pay the ſumm of Fifteén pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every younger ſon of ſuch Baron, ſo Charged as aforeſaid, ſhall pay the ſumm of Twelve pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man having the Title of a Peereſs of this Kingdom, or who takes place as ſuch by De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcent, or by any Grant from His Majeſty, or any of his Predeceſſors, having any Eſtate in Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe in this Kingdom, or that ſhall be in this Kingdom at the time of the execution of this Act, ſhall pay equal with any Peér of the ſame De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree. Every Widow of a Noble man, though Marryed to a Commoner, ſhall pay one full third part of what her former Huſband, whoſe Relict ſhe was, ſhould or ought to have paid, had he been living. Every Baronet of <hi>England,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:107354:6"/>Scotland,</hi> or <hi>Ireland,</hi> or <hi>Nova Scotia,</hi> and every Knight of the Bath, reſiding in this Kingdom at the time of the execution of this Act, or ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving any Eſtate in Lands, Tenements, or He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments in this Kingdom, ſhall pay he ſumm of Fifteén pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every perſon of the Degreé of a Knight Batchellor, ſhall pay Ten pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every perſon of the Degreé of an Eſquire, or ſo reputed, or owning, or wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting himſelf ſuch (other then ſuch as are repu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Eſquires for having beén, or being Mayor, or Sheriffs, or Members of any Corporation) and every perſon that is, or hath beén a Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of the Houſe of Commons, or born, or doth bear the Office of a Sheriff, or Juſtice of the Peace, or Deputy Lievtenant, reſiding in this Kingdom at the time of the execution of this Act, or having any Eſtate in Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments or Hereditaments within this Kingdom, ſhall pay the ſumm of Five pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> Eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry reputed Knight, Baronet, Baron, Viſcount and Earl, or who ſhall call or ſtile themſelves ſo, ſhall pay the ſame ſumm as they ſhould have beén lyable to pay if they really were of that Quality. Every Gentleman, or reputed Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman, or owning himſelf, or writing himſelf ſuch, inhabiting, or reſiding in this Kingdom, or having any Eſtate in Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments in this Kingdom, ſhall pay the ſumm of Five and twenty ſhillings <hi>ſterl.</hi> Except Gentlemen who ſhall not be worth Twenty pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> at the execution of this Act, ſhall pay Five ſhillings <hi>ſterl.</hi> and no more. Every Widow reſpectively reſiding in this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, or having any Eſtate within the ſame, ſhall pay One third part Rated by this Act on
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:107354:6"/>that Degreé of which the Huſband of ſuch Wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dow was in his life-time.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted, That every Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon under the Degreé of a Baron, being worth One hundred pounds in Goods, Chattels, or other Perſonal Eſtate, ſhall pay Five ſhillings; and that every Perſon as aforeſaid, worth in Perſonal Eſtate of any kind, Two hundred pounds <hi>Sterling,</hi> ſhall pay Ten Shillings; and every Perſon worth Threé hundred pounds in Perſonal Eſtate, as aforeſaid, ſhall pay Fifteén Shillings; and every perſon worth Four hundred pounds in perſonal Eſtate as aforeſaid, ſhall pay One pound <hi>Sterl.</hi> and every Perſon worth Five hundred pounds in Perſonal Eſtate as aforeſaid, ſhall pay One pound Five ſhillings; every Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon having in Perſonal Eſtate as aforeſaid, to the Value of One thouſand pounds, or up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards, ſhall pay the ſumm of Five pounds <hi>ſterl.</hi> Every Tenant, or Farmer of this Kingdom, who payeth not a greater Rent then Ten pounds <hi>ſterl. per ann.</hi> and every Shop-keéper Trades-man, or Artificer, not worth Ten pounds in Subſtance, ſhall pay for no more Children under the Age of Sixteén years, then two. Every Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant, or Farmer, paying above Ten pounds <hi>per ann.</hi> Rent, ſhall pay the ſumm of Two ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and Six pence. Every Tenant, or Far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, paying above Twenty pounds, <hi>per ann.</hi> Rent, ſhall pay the ſumm of Five ſhillings. Every Tenant, or Farmer, paying above Forty pounds Rent, <hi>per ann.</hi> ſhall pay the ſumm of Ten ſhillings. Every Tenant, or Farmer, paying above Sixty pounds <hi>per ann.</hi> Rent, ſhall pay the ſumm of Fifteén ſhillings. Every Farmer, or Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant paying One hundred pounds <hi>per ann.</hi> Rent,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:107354:7"/>or upward, ſhall pay the ſumm of One pound. Every Trades-man or Shop-keéper, that is worth Twenty pounds, or upwards, in Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonal Eſtate, ſhall pay the ſumm of Two ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and Six pence. Every Trades-man, or Shop-keéper worth Fifty pounds, or upwards, in Perſonal Eſtate, ſhall pay Five ſhillings. Every Shop-keéper, or Trades-man, worth One hundred pounds, or upwards, in Perſonal Eſtate, ſhall pay Ten ſhillings. Every Trades-man or Shop-keéper, worth Two hundred pounds in Perſonal Eſtate, ſhall pay Fifteén ſhillings. Every Trades-man or Shop-keéper, worth Threé hundred pounds, ſhall pay One pound. Every Trades-man, or Shop-keéper, worth Four hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds in Perſonal Eſtate, ſhall pay One pound Five ſhillings. Every Gray-Merchant, Merchant-Traveller, or Pedler, who uſually Travels with an Horſe, ſhall pay One pound. Every Gray-Merchant, Merchant-Traveller, or Pedler, who uſually Travels without an Horſe, ſhall pay Ten ſhillings. Every Perſon in Orders of the Romiſh Religion, ſhall pay Twelve ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and Six pence. And that all and every Perſon, except Women, Children under the Age of Sixteén, and ſuch as pay Two ſhillings, and no more, who have not already taken the Oaths, and Subſcribed the Declaration herein-after mentioned to His Majeſty: And who ſhall not voluntarily appear before the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or any two or more of them, and take the ſaid Oaths, and make, and ſubſcribe the Declaration herein-after mentioned; which Oath, any two or more of the Commiſſioners in this Act named, are hereby Impowered and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired to Adminiſter, and make an Entry or
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:107354:7"/>Memorandum thereof, and of making and Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribing the ſaid Declaration in ſome Book, to be kept for that purpoſe: Every ſuch Perſon who ſhall neglect to appear, or ſhall not take the Oath, and make, and Subſcribe the Decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration as aforeſaid, ſhall be charged with, and ſhall pay to His Majeſty double the ſumms, which by Force or Vertue of any Clauſe in this Act, he ſhould or ought to pay, or be charged with; to be Levyed, Collected, Anſwered, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covered and paid, in ſuch manner, and by ſuch ways and means, as are in this Act expreſſed and appointed, for, and concerning the Rates and ſumms hereby intended to be Doubled as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>Provided, nevertheleſs, That whereas certain Perſons, Diſſenters from the Church of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> commonly called Quakers, and now known to be ſuch, do ſcruple the taking any Oath, it ſhall be ſufficient for every ſuch Perſon to make and ſubſcribe the following Declaration.</p>
            <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="oath">
               <body>
                  <p>I A. B. do Sincerely Promiſe, and Solemnly De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare, before God and the World, That I will be True and Faithful to King WILLIAM.</p>
                  <p>And I Solemnly Profeſs and Declare, That I do from my Heart Abhor, Deteſt, and Renounce, as Impious and Heretical, that Damnable Doctrine and Poſition that Princes Excommunicated, or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prived by the Pope, or any Authority of the See of ROME, may be Depoſed or Murdered by their Subjects, or any other perſon whatſoever. And I do Declare that no Foreign Prince, Perſon, Prelate, State, or Potentate, hath, or ought to have any Power, Juriſdiction, Superiority, Preheminence, or Authority Eccleſiaſtical or Spiritual within this Realm.</p>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <pb n="12" facs="tcp:107354:8"/>
            <p>Which Declaration, any two or more of the Commiſſioners appointed for the Execution of this Act, are hereby Impowered and Required to take: And ſuch Perſon making, and Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribing the Declaration, ſhall not be Lyable to, or chargable with any of the Double Rates aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, That the ſeveral Summs of Money, ſo as aforeſaid, Limitted and Appointed to be paid, ſhall be Due and Payable for Two Years, Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mencing the Firſt Day of <hi>November,</hi> One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Six hundred Ninety ſeaven, and be Collected Quarterly by Four equal Payments; the Firſt Payment to be made on the Second Day of <hi>Febru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ary,</hi> in the Year of our Lord, One thouſand Six hundred Ninety ſeaven; the Second Payment to be made on the Second Day of <hi>May,</hi> in the Year of our Lord, One thouſand Six hundred Ninety eight; the Third Payment to be made on the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond Day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the Year of our Lord, One thouſand Six hundred Ninety eight; and the Fourth Payment to be made on the Second Day of <hi>November,</hi> which will be in the Year of our Lord God, One thouſand Six hundred and Ninety eight; the Fifth Payment to be made on the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond Day of <hi>February,</hi> which will be in the Year One thouſand Six hundred and Ninety eight; and Sixth Payment on the Second Day of <hi>May,</hi> in the Year One thouſand Six hundred and Ninety nine; the Seaventh Payment to be made on the Second Day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the Year One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Six hundred and Ninety nine; and Eighth and Laſt Payment to be made on the Second Day of <hi>November,</hi> in the ſaid Year, One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Six hundred and Ninety nine.</p>
            <pb n="13" facs="tcp:107354:9"/>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, That for the better Aſſeſſing, Ordering, and Levying of the ſeveral Summs of Money, ſo as aforeſaid Limitted and Appointed to be paid, and for the more effectual puting this Act in Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, all, and every the Perſons hereafter named, ſhall be Commiſſioners of, and for the ſeveral and reſpective Counties, Cities, Towns, and Places, hereafter named, for putting in Execution this preſent Act, and the Powers therein contain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, in the Counties, Cities, Towns, and Places, (That is to ſay)</p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Armagh.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The High-Sheriff for the time being, Sir <hi>Ni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cholas Acheſon,</hi> Bar. Sir <hi>Henry Yichburne,</hi> Kt. <hi>Arthur Brownlow, Marmaduke Coghill, Samuel Doppin, Stephen Ludlow, Edward Reyly, William Richardſon, William Mollineux, Hamlet Obins, Downham Cope, Edward Harriſon, John Hamil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton, Rich Chappell, William Blacker, Henry Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chardſon, Walter Dawſon, Roger Hall, Henry Hunter, Hans Hamilton, James Maxwell, Richard Whaley,</hi> Eſquires, The Soveraign of <hi>Armagh,</hi> for the time being, the Portreéve of <hi>Charlemont,</hi> for the time being, <hi>Rath Jones, Thomas Clarck</hi> of <hi>Ardreſs, Daniel Madden, Thomas Bond, James mc. Kean, George Maxwell, John Hamilton</hi> of <hi>Hamil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tons Bawn,</hi> Gentlemen, Captain <hi>James Manſon, Francis Nevill,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                  <hi>William Scott, John Ball, Abraham Ball, Thomas Clarck</hi> of <hi>Portadown,</hi> Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen, <hi>John Holtrige,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Antrim.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Arthur Longford,</hi> Bar. Captain <hi>John Chi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheſter,</hi>
                  <pb n="14" facs="tcp:107354:10"/>Sir <hi>Robert Adaire, Arthur Upton, Hugh Colvill, James mc. Cartney, Edward Harriſon, God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frey Walker, Hercules Davis, Henry Davis, Charles ô Neal, Edward Stafford, Thomas Dawſon, Robert Dalway, Alexander Dalway,</hi> Eſquires. The So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veraign of <hi>Belfaſt</hi> for the time being, <hi>Robert Leaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, George mc. Cartney,</hi> Eſquires, <hi>Edward Brice,</hi> Gentleman, <hi>Clothworthy Upton,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                  <hi>Arthur mc. Cartney, Edward Clements,</hi> Gent. <hi>Richard Dob,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Edward Ellis, William Shaw</hi> of <hi>Ganavay, John ô Neal, Henry mc. Collagh, Robert Dovil,</hi> Eſquires, Doctor <hi>John Peacock, Henry Shaw, William Shaw</hi> of <hi>Balligally,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>William Laftly, Benjamin Gallant, Charles Stewart William Shaw</hi> of <hi>Buſh, John Donelſon, George Buttle,</hi> Eſquires, <hi>William Crawford</hi> and <hi>Thomas Crawford, William Thompſon, Robert Haran, James Tanas, James Johnſton, Cornelius Crumble, John Pierſe, John Charlton, William Cloſe, Richard Harriſſon, Thomas Cornwall,</hi> Gentlemen; <hi>John Latham, Warham Jemmet,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>James Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton, Benjamin Adaire,</hi> Gentlemen; <hi>Samuel Sincly, Edmond Reynolds, John Reynolds,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>James Crawford, Robert Harper, Richard Nuton, Bryan mc. Manus, Patrick Hamilton</hi> of <hi>Belfaſt, William Adaire, John Dobbin, William Dobin, James mc. Collagh, James Boyd, Neal Boy mc. Neal</hi> of the <hi>Henry Andrew, Hugh mc. Cullam, Henry Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loughby, Henry Sheads, Francis Andrew, Andrew mc. Calvey, William Boyd, John Delap, William Boyd, John Michall, Alexander mc. Kay, Alexander Watſon,</hi> and <hi>John Walkinton,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of the Town of <hi>Carickfergus.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Mayor of <hi>Carickfergus</hi> for the time being,
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:107354:10"/>the Sheriffs of the ſame for the time being, <hi>Her<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cules Davis, Henry Davis,</hi> Eſquires; and <hi>Marma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duke Newton,</hi> Gentleman:</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Catherlaugh.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The High-Sheriff for the time being, Sir <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Butler, John Allen, Philip Savage, Wentworth Harman, John Tench, Thomas Burdett, Richard Woleſſy, Urban Vigors, Edmond Jones, John Beau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>champ, John Brown,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Dolway, John Bernard, James Cox,</hi> Arch-Deacon, <hi>Robert Harris,</hi> and <hi>Thomas Fox,</hi> Clerks.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Cavan.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Honourable Mr. Iuſtice <hi>Coot,</hi> Sir <hi>Francis Hamilton,</hi> Baronet; <hi>Francis White, Thomas Aſh, Robert Saunders, Francis Butler, John Warburton, Samuel Townly, Thomas Townly, Joſeph Pratt, John Maxwell, John Coyne, Robert Clements, Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niel French, Arnold Cosby, Henry Palmer, Charles Hampſon, Alexander Sanderſon, Edward Daven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port, Walter Pollard,</hi> Eſquires; Dean <hi>Enoch Rider, William Handſon, Robert Maxwell, Anthony lvi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon,</hi> Clerks; <hi>Robert Craige,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                  <hi>Brockhill New<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burgh, Henry Guillyms, Thomas Hemming, Thomas Humes, George Ruſſell, Samuel Wilſon, John Robinſon, John Price,</hi> and <hi>Patrick Everey,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Clare.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Henry Ingoldsby,</hi> Sir <hi>Donat ô Brian,</hi> Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ronets; <hi>Francis Burton,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                  <hi>Francis Gore,</hi> and <hi>James Hamilton</hi> of <hi>Tullymore,</hi> the Honourable
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:107354:11"/>
                  <hi>John ô Brian, Simon Purden, Henry Bridgeman, Edmond Perry, Thomas Spaight,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Roan, John Cuſack.</hi> Gentlemen; <hi>Mountifort We<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrop, William Smith,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Hawkins,</hi> Clerk: <hi>William Butler,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                  <hi>George Calpoys, Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trick Connel,</hi> Gentlemen; <hi>Samuel Burton, Thomas Hickman, George Stammer, David Bendon, Nicho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>las Weſtby,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Patrick Fitz-Simmons,</hi> Clerk; <hi>Henry Lee, Walter Hickman, James Mac Donnell,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>William Smith, Richard Lee, Henry Hickman, George Hickman</hi> of <hi>Ballickett,</hi> Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men; <hi>Auguſtin Fitz-Gerald,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                  <hi>William Fitz-Gerald,</hi> Gentleman; <hi>Neptune Blood,</hi> Dean of <hi>Kil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenoragh,</hi> and <hi>Timothy ô Brien</hi> of <hi>Smithſtowne.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the City of <hi>Cork.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Colonel <hi>Theobald Purcell, Allen Broderick,</hi> His Majeſty's Sollicitor General, Alderman <hi>Robert Rogers,</hi> Doctor <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>alter Neale,</hi> Mr. <hi>Edward Synge,</hi> the Mayor and Sheriffs of <hi>Cork</hi> for the time being, <hi>Thomas Piggot,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Alderman <hi>Newenham,</hi> Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derman <hi>Howell, William Newſtead,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man <hi>Hore,</hi> Alderman <hi>Crofts,</hi> Alderman <hi>Crow,</hi> Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derman <hi>Charters, John Speed,</hi> Merchant, Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain <hi>William Dunſcomb,</hi> Captain <hi>Epenetus Croſs,</hi> and Captain <hi>John Traverſe.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Cork.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>St. John Broderick,</hi> Knight, <hi>Thomas Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derick,</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Allan Broderick,</hi> Eſquire, His Majeſty's Sollicitor General; <hi>Henry Boyle, Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Fitz-Gerald, Edward Southwell, James Walter, Edward Riggs, Francis Bernard, William Jepſon, Laurence Clayton, Edward Denny, John Hayes,
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:107354:12"/>Charles Boyle, John Ormsby, Francis Brewſter, Charles Oliver, James Barry, Robert Foulks, Piercy Freake, Brian Townſend, Thomas Beecher, Edward Richardſon, Samuel Maurice,</hi> and <hi>Robert Pooly,</hi> Eſquires; Sir <hi>John Mead,</hi> Knight; <hi>Francis Hodder, George Symmes, William Carr, John Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vis, John Baily,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Thomas Crooke, Edward Worth, Richard Traverſe, Richard Hutchins, Daniel Beaniſh</hi> and <hi>John Lee,</hi> Eſquires; the Mayor of <hi>Youghall,</hi> the Soveraign of <hi>Kinſale,</hi> the Provoſt of <hi>Bandon,</hi> the Soveraign of <hi>Middleton,</hi> and the Soveraign of <hi>Charlevill</hi> for the time being; Sir <hi>Mathew Dean,</hi> Knight, <hi>John Cook, Richard Yeats, John Luther, Edward Nicholas,</hi> and <hi>Jaſper Lucas,</hi> Merchants; <hi>William Bollard, Nicholas Brumby, Richard Wakeham, William Wakeham, Peter Betts<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth, Thomas Piggott, John Traverſe, John Bowles, John Wakeham, William Supple, Samuel Maynard, John Montgomery, Stephen Moore, Boyle Ald<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth, Emanuel Moore, Henry Tonſon, Joſeph Jervis, Henry Beecher, Anthony Butler, Samuel Pomroy, Thomas Purdun, Arthur Hyde,</hi> Captain <hi>Elwell, Jonas Stowell,</hi> Senior, <hi>Jonas Stowell,</hi> Iu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nior, and <hi>Robert Gookin,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Arthur Keefe, Gabriel Solden,</hi> Mr. <hi>Mountiford, Thomas Burrowes,</hi> and <hi>Thomas Chidleigh,</hi> Gentlemen; <hi>William Newſtead, Robert Couran, Thomas Hyde, Edward Dodſworth,</hi> and <hi>Henry Rice,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Brailsford, Apollos Morris, Barrachias Wallis, Walter Croker, Henry Wallis, Charles New<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, George Chinery, James Mauſerge, William Babington, John Silver, Richard Betteſworth, William Thornhill, George Rogers, Francis Smith, John VVat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kins,</hi> and <hi>Henry Boreman,</hi> Eſquires, <hi>Epenetus Croſs, John Baily,</hi> Senior, <hi>John Gilman, John VVallis,</hi> and <hi>Nicholas Lyſaght; Arthur Bernard,</hi> and <hi>VVil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:107354:13"/>VVarner,</hi> Eſquires, and <hi>Edward Howſe,</hi> Gentleman.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of the City of <hi>Dublin.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Lord Mayor, Recorder and Sheriffs for the time being. Maſter Chancelor of the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequor, Mr. Attorney-General, Mr. Sollicitor-General, the Commiſſioners of his Majeſty's Revenue of <hi>Ireland</hi> for the time being, Sir <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Billington,</hi> Sir <hi>Francis Brewſter,</hi> Sir <hi>Hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phery Jervis,</hi> Sir <hi>John Rogerſon,</hi> Adlermen <hi>John Smith,</hi> Alderman <hi>George Blackhall,</hi> Alderman <hi>William Watts,</hi> Alderman <hi>Bartholomew, Van<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>humrigh</hi> Alderman <hi>Thomas Quin,</hi> Alderman <hi>Anthony Percy,</hi> Alderman <hi>Marks Ransford,</hi> Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derman <hi>Samuell Walton,</hi> Alderman <hi>John Page,</hi> Alerman <hi>Charles Thompſon,</hi> Alderman <hi>Francis Stoite,</hi> Sr <hi>John Coghill,</hi> Sir <hi>Patrick Dunne, Stephen Ludlow, Marmaduke Coghill, Thomas Til<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, Standiſh Hartſtonge, Elnathan Lumm, Edward Wingfield, Robert Moleſworth, Edmund Rennell, Edward Richardſon, Wentworth Harman, John Redding William Mollineux,</hi> Doctor <hi>Thomas Mol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lyneux, Robert Peppard, Gideon Delaune, James Mac Cartney, William Handcock</hi> the Elder, <hi>John Allen, Anderſon Saunders, Robert Saunders, Roger Moore, George Warburton, John Warburton, Anthony Towers, James Tiſdell, Daniel Wibrants, Benjamin Burton, Charles Delane, Edward Deane, Chriſtopher Uſher, John Uſher, James Hamilton,</hi> of <hi>Tullamore</hi> and <hi>Stephen Stanley,</hi> Eſquires; Collonel <hi>John Lovett,</hi> Collonel <hi>Robert Ecklin, William Connelly,</hi> Collonel <hi>Henry Cunningham, Samuel Dopping,</hi> Sir <hi>Arthur Cole, Abel Ram, Charles Cambell</hi> Sir <hi>Francis Blundell,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:107354:13"/>Ingoldsby, William Neave, Edward Reyly, Her<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culus Davis, St. Leger Gilbert,</hi> Eſquires; Sir <hi>Patrick Dun,</hi> Knight, <hi>Robert Ormsby, John Orms<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by, Richard Thompſon, Charles Deering, Edward Wingfield, Thomas Brodrick,</hi> and <hi>William Robin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> 
                  <hi>William Cairnes, Ralph Gore, Fauſtin Cuppaidge, Thomas Twigg, Richard Cooke, VVilliam Keating, Daniel Miles, Robert King, John Rotten,</hi> Gentlemen; <hi>Robert Curtis,</hi> and <hi>Joſeph Budden,</hi> Eſquires; and all the Members of the Houſe of Commons in and about <hi>Dublin.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Dublin.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Robert Rochford,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Sir <hi>Richard Bulckely,</hi> Sir <hi>Arthur Cole,</hi> Sir <hi>Richard Bellingham,</hi> and Sir <hi>Thomas Domvile,</hi> Baronets, Sir <hi>John Coghill,</hi> Sir <hi>William Domvile</hi> and Sir <hi>Walter Plunket,</hi> Knights; <hi>Allan Broderick, Robert Mouldſworth, Edward Deane, John Redding, Thomas Aſh, John Tench, Thomas Pooly, John Allen, Denny Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>champ, Richard Forſter, Joſeph Deane,</hi> Senr. <hi>George Wallis, Daniel Redding,</hi> Senr. <hi>John Stepny, Robert Peppard, Thomas Keightly, John South, Chriſtopher Carlton, Marmaduke Coghil, Richard Thompſon, William Neave, Henry Fernly, Joſeph Deane,</hi> Iunr. <hi>Joſeph Stepny, Richard Morris, Thomas Stepeny, Dixie Coddington, Chriſtopher Uſher, John Price, Iſaac Dobſon, Bernard Brown, George Warburton, Joſeph Budden,</hi> and <hi>Agmun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſhham Veſy,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Daniel Reading</hi> Iunr. Gent. <hi>Henry Cooly, William Malineux, Robert Curtis, James Grace</hi> and <hi>Edward Corker,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqs</abbr>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="20" facs="tcp:107354:14"/>
               <head>For the County of <hi>Donnegall.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The High Sheriff for the time being, Sir <hi>William Gore</hi> Baronet; Colonel <hi>Guſtavus Hamil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton</hi> Colonel <hi>Henry Cuningham, Charles Hamil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton, Andrew Knox, John Forward, John Hamil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton, Hugh Hamill, John Montgomery, Francis Folliot, William Gore, William Connely, Charles Melvin, Henry Langford, Humphry May, Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Stewart, William Wray, Henry Hart, George Vaghan, Patrick Hamilton</hi> and <hi>Edward Hariſon,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> Capt. <hi>William Hamilton,</hi> Capt. <hi>William Cun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingham,</hi> Capt. <hi>Francis Hamilton,</hi> Capt. <hi>Robert Baird, Ralph Gore, William Sampſon,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                  <hi>Thomas Mac Caſland, Alexander Cunningham</hi> of <hi>Aghen; Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Knox,</hi> Gentlemen, the Warden of <hi>Lifford,</hi> for the time being, the Provoſt of <hi>Donegall, Kil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leybeggs, Balliſhannon,</hi> and <hi>St. Johnſton,</hi> for the time being, <hi>Henry Brook, Andrew Knox, VVil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Cairy, Robert Mortimer, James Vaughan, Michael Huetſon, Robert Spence, Thomas Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kinſon, Triſtram Swetenham, John Cowan, Charles Colhoone, VVilliam VValker, Alexander Nisbit, James Nisbett, Andrew Lindſey, John Evans, Edward Cairy,</hi> and <hi>John Henderſon,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of the Town of <hi>Drogheda.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Mayor and Sheriffs for the time being, <hi>Charles</hi> Lord <hi>Moore,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry Tichburn, John Stoker, Edward Singelton, Richard Jackſon, Thomas Percivall, VVilliam Elwood, Henry Ni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cholaſs, Joſeph Tomlinſon, VVilliam Newton, James Mead, John Graham, Richard Pitts,</hi> Aldermen; <hi>Caleb Gay,</hi> and <hi>Richard VVhaly,</hi> Eſquires.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="21" facs="tcp:107354:14"/>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Downe.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>John Trever.</hi> Sir <hi>John Maghill. Nicholas Bagnoll, James Hamilton,</hi> of <hi>Tallymore, Nicholas Price, Mathew Ford, William Shaw, Edward Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſon, Fredrick Porter, Robert Ecklin, Patrick Savage, James Montgomery, John Ecklin, Gowin Hamilton, William Hamilton, John Hawkins, Henry Hunter, John Norice, John Gibbons, James Baile, John Ellſmeer, John Latham,</hi> The Honourable <hi>Michael Hill,</hi> Eſquire, <hi>James Hamilton,</hi> of <hi>Ban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gor, Francis Anneſly, Hans Hamilton, James Slone, Clotworthy Upton, Charles Campbell, David Camp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bell, Francis Hall, Hugh Muntgomery, George Roſſe,</hi> of <hi>Portavo, Arthur Maxwell, Samuel Warring, John Haltridge, Roger Hall,</hi> Captain <hi>Alexander Steward, Vere Ward, Thomas Knox, Richard John<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſton</hi> and <hi>John Montomery,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Lath<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>am, Francis Allen, Patrick Hamilton, Mathew Stothard, John Smith, James Hewſon, John Saun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, William Catherwood, Henry Maxwell,</hi> Capt. <hi>Evan Humphries, William Neaven, Hugh Maxwell, Robert Hawkens, Philip Wilkiſon, James Hamil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> of <hi>Derryboy, Roger Briſto, Alexander Brown, John Blackwood,</hi> Junior, and <hi>Alexander Hamil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> and <hi>George Roſſe,</hi> of <hi>Carny,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Fermanagh.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Sheriff of the ſaid County for the time being, Sir <hi>Guſtavus Hume,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>James Caldwell,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>Michael Cole,</hi> Knight, Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lonel <hi>Abraham Creighton,</hi> Collonel <hi>James Corry,</hi> Doctor <hi>Chriſtopher Irwin, Charles Balfour, Hugh Montgomery,</hi> of <hi>Carow, William Archdale, Charles
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:107354:15"/>Wallis, Hugh Montgomery,</hi> of Derrygonelly, <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Balfour,</hi> Eſquires; Captain <hi>James Creigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> Captain <hi>John Corry, Gilbert Eccles, David Rynde, Jaſon Haſſart, Edward Davis,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> The Provoſt of <hi>Enniskilling,</hi> for the time being, <hi>James Aghenlect, Walter Johnſton,</hi> Gentlemen, Captain <hi>John Irwin,</hi> Captain <hi>Robert Clarke,</hi> Sir <hi>William Gore,</hi> Sir <hi>Triſtram Berrisford,</hi> and Sir <hi>Henry Tichburne,</hi> Baronets.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Galway.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>George St. George,</hi> Knight, <hi>John Eyre,</hi> Eſquire, Sir <hi>George St. George</hi> Baronet, <hi>Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lonel Richard St. George, Gilbert Ormsby, William Caulfield, Frederick Trench, Henry Peirce, John Ormsby, John Morgan, John Neyland, Richard Whaly, Robert Maſon, Thomas Croſſdale, Samuel Eyre, John Lopdell, Edward Eyre,</hi> Eſquires; the High Sheriff for the time being, <hi>Thomas Stanton, Edward Crow,</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Robert Shaw, John Carter, Oliver Carter, John Taylor, Thomas Cunys, Edward Blackney, Jeremy Morgan, Jacob Spike, Thomas Crookſhanke, William Gunter, Richard Warren, John Broughton</hi> Iunr. <hi>Lodowick Pringle, Francis Muxley, Conn Mitchell, William Davis,</hi> and <hi>Edward Wilſon,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of the Town of <hi>Gallway.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Mayor and Recorder for the time being or their reſpective Deputy's, the Sheriffs of the ſaid Town for the time being, <hi>Thomas Revett, Thomas Simcocks, Thomas Cartwright, Thomas Yeeden, Iohn Gerry,</hi> Aldermen, Sir <hi>George St. George,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>George St. George,</hi> Knight,
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:107354:15"/>Collonel <hi>Richard St. George, Robert Ormsby, Iohn Eyre, Edward Eyre, Iohn Ormsby, Iohn Ravett,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Robert Shaw, Robert Witherington,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>Iames Rivettvigie,</hi> Merchant.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Kerry.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Lord Baron of <hi>Kerry,</hi> the Honourable Captain <hi>William Fitz-Maurice,</hi> the Honourable <hi>James Fitz-Maurice, Edward Denny,</hi> Senior, Eſqs. the She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riff for the time being, the Honourable <hi>Henry Petty, William Sands, John Haſſett, Edward Denny,</hi> Iu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nior, <hi>Barry Denny, Samuel Maurice, James VVal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler, Frederick Mullins, David Croſby, VVhittall Brown, Theobald Purcell, Andrew Young, Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Ponſenby, John Haſſet of Killorglin, Samuel Raymond, Patrick Crosby, Rowland Bateman, John Bateman, VVilliam Crosby, Robert Haſſett, Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Shortcliffe, John VValker, Richard Brown, Joſeph Morris, Charles VVrenn, Henry Staughton, Timothy Euraghty, Charles Monk,</hi> Dean <hi>John Richards, Richard Burch, Lancelot Glanville, James Comor, Samuel VVilſon, Iames Bland, Thomas Pal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, Ioſias Kenington, Richard Orpin, Iohn Raw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lins, Iaſper Morris, Richard Burch, Iohn Sands</hi> and <hi>Francis Downs.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Kilkenny.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Chriſtopher Wandesford,</hi> Baronet; Sir <hi>John Mead,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry Weymes,</hi> Knights; Collonel <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Ponſonby, Agmundiſham Cuffe, Ebenezer Warren, Arthur Buſh, Blaney Sandford, Edward Worth, Chriſtopher Huetſon, Edward May, Samuel Booth, Robert Stopford, Balthazer Cramer, Arthur Webb, John Eaton, Amias Buſh, John Langriſh,
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:107354:16"/>George Read, John Baker, Thomas Crawford, Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Deane, Arthur St. George, Joſeph Bradſhaw,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Thomas Scurfield, Edward Briſco, Ralph Rell, Joſeph Rell, Pierce Brian</hi> of <hi>Bawnemore, Paul Gore, John Warring, Richard Connell, John Jones, Nathaniel Boyſe</hi> and <hi>Darby Egan,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> 
                  <hi>Abel But<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler, Charles Gore, James Agar, Jonathan Whitby, William Headen, Patrick Welſh, Joſeph Wheeler, Thomas Manſell, William Deys, John Biſhop, John Villers, John Barnes, Daniel Manſergh, William Hawkins</hi> and <hi>Joſeph Lodge,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the City of <hi>Kilkenny.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Mayor, Recorder, and Sheriffs for the time being; Sir <hi>Chriſtopher Wandesford,</hi> Baro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>net; <hi>Standiſh Hartſtongue,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Recorder, <hi>Eben<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ezer Warren, Richard Connel, Joſhua Helſham, John Pape, Iſaac Muckins,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Joſias Hay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dock, Patrick Connell, Albert Butler, John Garnet</hi> and <hi>John Warring,</hi> Aldermen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Kildare.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Lord Viſcount <hi>Ely,</hi> the Honourable <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Fitz-Gerald</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Sir <hi>Francis Blundel,</hi> Sir <hi>Kildare Burrows,</hi> Baronets; Sir <hi>John Euſtace,</hi> Knight; <hi>George Fitz-Gerald, Iames Barry, Richard Nevil, Thomas Medlicot, Iohn Davis, Maurice Keating, Richard Lock, Francis VVeymes, Robert Graydon, Paul Davis, Robert Dixon, Iohn Allen, VVentworth Harman, Francis Anneſly, Maurice Anneſly, John Anneſly, Edward Stratford, Ag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mundiſham Vezy, VVilliam Mollineux, Garret VVeiſely, Richard Meredith, Henry Warren, Charles Rickeſeis, Dudly Cooly, Henry Cooly,
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:107354:17"/>Raphael Hunt, Ieffery Paul, Iohn Ailmer, Iames VVhite, VVilliam Bruerton, Iohn Aylmer,</hi> Iu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nior, <hi>Richard VVibrow, VValter White, Francis Spring, Thomas Twigg, Theobald Bourk, William Chavinor, Benjamin Fiſh, George Medlicot, William Harbourne,</hi> and <hi>William Southerby,</hi> Eſquires, <hi>William Knight,</hi> Clerk, <hi>Alexander Graydon, Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Wright, Bartholomew Rigg,</hi> and <hi>Henry Doyle,</hi> Gentlemen. The ſeveral Soveraigns for the time being, of the <hi>Naas, Kildare, Athy,</hi> and <hi>Hariſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>town.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the Kings County.</head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Francis Blundell,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>Lawrence Parſons,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>George Harbert,</hi> Baronet, <hi>William Parſons, Duke Gifford, John Eyre, Thomas Leſtrange Richard Warburton,</hi> Senior, <hi>William Sprigg, John Weaver, John Moore, Samuel Rolls, Hector Vaghan, John Baldwin,</hi> Seinor, <hi>John Bald<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>win,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Richard Hanſard, Robert Leſtrange, John Wakely, Albert Nesbit, Jeffry Lyons, Thomas Moore, Jonathan Darby, Samuel Moſs, Martin Baldwin, Richard Warburton,</hi> Iunior, <hi>George Warburton, Henry Weſtonray,</hi> Eſqs. <hi>William Nelſon,</hi> Clerk, <hi>Daniel Tomlinſon,</hi> Clerk, <hi>George Lowther,</hi> Clerk, <hi>Medhop Loyd, Richard Luther, John Sey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, Anthony Carroll, Humphry Minchin, William Witherill, Peter Holmes, Maurice Keating,</hi> Capt. <hi>Oliver Bingly, Phillip Moore, James Sterling, Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Baggot, Miles Baggot, Charles Wenman,</hi> Eſquires; Captain <hi>Charles Steward, Francis Lam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert, George Fryſſel, Archibald Armſtrong, Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thaniel Taylor, John Ridgway, John Tarlton, John Cradock, William, Minchin Randall Cook,
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:107354:18"/>Bigo Honſy, William Armſtrong Francis Clarke, Phi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lip Wenman,</hi> and <hi>William Vaughan,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Leytrim.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>George St. George,</hi> Sir <hi>William Gore,</hi> Sir <hi>Robert Gore,</hi> and Sir <hi>Francis Hamilton,</hi> Baronets, <hi>John Renolds, Theophilus Jones, Gilbert King, Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Lander, William Gore, Morgan Cunigam, Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Crafton, Robert Galbrath, John French, Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thur Cooper, John Mahon, Edward Reynell, Ralph Gore, William Smith,</hi> and <hi>William Parks,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> Capt. <hi>Edward Johnſton,</hi> Capt. <hi>William Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, William Lander,</hi> Iunior, <hi>John Peyton, Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Ellis,</hi> and <hi>John Crofton,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>VVil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Cuningham,</hi> and <hi>VVhitelaw,</hi> Clerks, the Soveraign of <hi>James Town,</hi> and the Provoſt of <hi>Carrick,</hi> for the time being.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Limerick.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Edward Crofton,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>Thomas Southell,</hi> Baronet, and Sir <hi>Standiſh Hartſtonge,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>VVilliam King,</hi> Knight, <hi>George Evans,</hi> the Younger, <hi>Chicheſter Phillips, Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſh Hartſtonge,</hi> the Younger, <hi>Chidley Coot, Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſh Hartſtonge,</hi> the Elder, <hi>Charles Oliver, John Ormsby, Joſeph Stephny, VVilliam Trenchard, John Piggott, George Evans.</hi> Senior<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                  <hi>Ralph Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, John Odell, Michael Serl, Henry Widdenham, Richard Stephens, David Wilſon, Robert Taylor, Thomas Monſell, William Blackney John Croker, Richard VValler, James VValler, Thomas Holmes, George King, John Parker, Henry Iohnſon, Hugh Maſſey Thomas Roſe, Henry Ailmer, VVilliam Ryvers, John Bury, William Langford,</hi> the Younger,
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:107354:18"/>Eſquires; <hi>Sampſon Cox, Edward Blenerhaſett John Bayly, Edward Croker, Thomas Fitz-Gerald,, Iohn Gabbot, Owen Cutbert,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>Nicholas Wesby,</hi> and <hi>Edward May,</hi> Eſquires.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the City of <hi>Limerick.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Mayor for the time being, Sir <hi>Joſeph Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liamſon,</hi> and Sir <hi>William King,</hi> Knights, <hi>Joſeph Coghlan,</hi> Eſquire, Recorder; Dean <hi>Ezekiel Webb, Ralph Wilſon,</hi> and <hi>Edmond Perry,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Gribble Robert Smith, George Roch, John Craven, John Ford, Edward VVeight</hi> and <hi>Simon VVhite,</hi> Aldermen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Longford.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Robert Newcomen,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>John Edg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth,</hi> Knight, Sir <hi>Walter Plunket,</hi> Knight, The Honourable <hi>William VVolſely, Ambroſe Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger, Wentworth Harman,</hi> Eſquires, <hi>John Kerr,</hi> Dean of <hi>Ardagh, Charles Fox, Anthony Shep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herd, Arthur Aghmooty,</hi> Senior, <hi>Arthur Newcomen, Francis Edgworth, John Percivall, John Ahmooty, Theophilus Jones, Samuel Forth, Frake Sandys, Mathew Wilder, Robert Edgworth, Arthur Agh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mooty,</hi> Iunior, <hi>William Hide, Francis VVilſon, John Kenedy, Richard Gardiner,</hi> and <hi>Thomas Hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cock,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Wilſon,</hi> Clerk, <hi>John Green,</hi> Clerk, The Soveraign of <hi>Longford,</hi> for the time being, The Soveraign of <hi>Lanesburrough,</hi> for the time being, the Soveraign of <hi>St. John<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtown,</hi> for the time being, and the Soveraign of <hi>Granard,</hi> for the time being.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the City and County of <hi>London-derry.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Mayors and Recorders of <hi>London-derry</hi>
                  <pb n="28" facs="tcp:107354:19"/>and <hi>Colraine,</hi> for the time being, the Sheriffs of the City and County of <hi>London-derry,</hi> for the time being; Sir <hi>Triſtram Berrisford,</hi> Sir <hi>Arthur Langford,</hi> Sir <hi>Robert Staples,</hi> Baronets; <hi>William Jackſon, David Cairnes, Bartholomew Vanhomrigh, Henry Langford</hi> and <hi>William Connelly,</hi> Eſquires, <hi>William Smith, Jervis Squire, Alexander Lecky, James Lenox, Henry Long, Henry Aſh, Horace Kenedy, Thomas Moncrefie,</hi> all Aldermen of the City of <hi>London-derry; Alexander Skipton, Charles Norman, John Mogridge, John Corran</hi> and <hi>John Harvey,</hi> Gentlemen. <hi>Edward Brooks,</hi> Merchant, <hi>Hugh Rowly, William Cuningham, Thomas Daw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon,</hi> and <hi>Nicholas Downing,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Hugh Rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, Thomas Aſh, Adam Downing, William Pal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, Samuel Right</hi> and <hi>John Howey,</hi> Senior, Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen. <hi>Edward Carey</hi> and <hi>William Gage,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> The Provoſt of <hi>Newtown</hi> for the time being; <hi>George Carey, George Church, William Bacon, Edward Bacon, Robert Bacon, Robert Dent, George Thornton</hi> and <hi>Henry Brown,</hi> Gentlemen. <hi>George Cunning</hi> and <hi>Thomas Church,</hi> Eſquires. Collonel <hi>Thomas Blaire, George Canning, Charles Church,</hi> Iunior; <hi>John Hodgſon</hi> and <hi>Dominick Heyland,</hi> Gentlemen. <hi>Triſtram Beresford</hi> and <hi>William God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frey,</hi> Eſquires. <hi>Arthur Church, John Galt</hi> and <hi>Edward Barwick,</hi> Aldermen of <hi>Colerain. Michael Berrisford, Arthur Carey, Thomas Spaight</hi> and <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Lance,</hi> Gentlemen. <hi>Nicholas Averall, John Thompſon,</hi> Iunior, and <hi>John Galt,</hi> Iunior, Merchants. <hi>Richard Lynham, James Buoy,</hi> and <hi>John Oliver,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Louth.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The High Sheriff for the time being; Sir <hi>John
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:107354:20"/>Hanmore,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry Tichborne,</hi> Knights and Baronets; Sir <hi>Thomas Forteſcue,</hi> Knight, <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Bellingham, James Tiſdale, John Pepper, Norman Garſtin, Blaney Townley, Edward Singleton, Arthur Brownlowe, William Barton, Timothy Armitage, Brabazon Moor, Robert Alway,</hi> and <hi>Kilnor Brazier,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Ruxton, Anthony Barry, James Leigh, John Smith,</hi> Gent. Alderman <hi>John Graham, Roger Bury, Thomas Clarke,</hi> Gentlemen; <hi>Caleb Gay, Jeremiah Smith,</hi> Eſquires, <hi>Philip Vincent,</hi> Senior, the Portreeves of <hi>Atherdee</hi> for the time being; the Bailiff of <hi>Dundalk</hi> for the time being; the So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veraign of <hi>Carlingford</hi> for the time being; the Soveraign of <hi>Dumleer</hi> for the time being.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Mayo.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Henry Bingham,</hi> Sir <hi>Arthur Shane,</hi> Baro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nets; <hi>John Byngham, Willam Gore, Gyles Vander<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lure, William Palmer, Edward Eyre, Robert Mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler, Thomas Bell, John Mathew, Thomas Burditt, Robert Miller,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Robert Bell, Francis Pal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Thomas Brown, Thomas Jones, Samuel Lindſey, Robert Ormsby, Mathew Bell, John Sheridan, Robert Ormsby,</hi> Iunior, and <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Cuffe,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Meath.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Right Honourable the Lord <hi>Moore,</hi> the Chancellor of the Exchequer, <hi>Oliver Lambert,</hi> Eſquire; Sir <hi>Arthur Langford,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>goldsby,</hi> Baronets; Sir <hi>Henry Tichburne,</hi> Knight and Baronet; Sir <hi>John Dillon,</hi> Knight, <hi>Thomas Blith,</hi> Eſquire, Sir <hi>Charles Fielding,</hi> Knight; <hi>Andrew Ram, William Napper, Robert Johnſon,
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:107354:21"/>Arthur Meredith, Francis Osburne, Thomas Taylor, Charles Meredith, Garret Weſley, James Napper,</hi> Eſquires, Doctor <hi>Molineux, Edward Corker, Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Forth, Michael Shields, Samuel Bull, Henry Langford, Robert Hopford, Lancelot Dowdall, Jo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeph Deane, Anthony Towers, Charles Lambert, Henry Osburne</hi> of <hi>Dardiſtown, Stephen Ludlow, John Warburton,</hi> Eſquires, Major <hi>George Pepper, Symon Pepper, Hugh Mervyn, John Leigh, John Grimes, Edward Singleton, William Elwood,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> 
                  <hi>Nathaniel Elwood, Anthony Berry,</hi> Gentlemen. <hi>Charles Campbell,</hi> Eſquire; <hi>Richard Shinton, Hen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Osbourne</hi> of <hi>Knowth, Thomas Garret,</hi> Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men. <hi>Joſeph Woodward, William Williams, Samuel Jackſon,</hi> Eſquires, <hi>Thomas Nicholſon,</hi> Gentleman, <hi>Henry Meredith,</hi> Eſquire; Major <hi>John Pepper, Henry Codogan,</hi> Eſquire. <hi>Alexander Kent, Joſeph Dean,</hi> Iunior, Gentlemen. <hi>Darcy Wentworth, George Wentworth, Nathaniel Bull, John Wade,</hi> Eſquires. <hi>Charles Wade</hi> of <hi>Clonebray,</hi> Gentleman, <hi>John Wood, John Wood, Robert Alway, John Perci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>val, Samuel Dopping, Thomas Loftus, Joſeph Pratt, Benjamin Pratt,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Pratt,</hi> Gentleman. <hi>William Conelly, Richard Jones, John Jones</hi> of <hi>Fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſan, Iſaac Holdwright, Iohn Hawkſhaw,</hi> Eſquires. Portreeve of <hi>Trim</hi> for the time being; Soveraign of <hi>Kells</hi> for the time being; Portreeve of <hi>Navan</hi> for the time being; <hi>Duke Iefford, Iames Tiſdall, Edward Swan,</hi> Eſquires. Alderman <hi>Iames Van<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bobbart,</hi> Captain <hi>William Ingoldsby, Marmaduke Coghill, Oliver Moore, Thomas Aſhe,</hi> Eſquires. <hi>Samuel Gwithers,</hi> Gentleman. <hi>William Palmer,</hi> Eſquire. Sir <hi>Iohn Coghill,</hi> Knight. <hi>Robert Smith, Robert Moleſworth, Hugh Morgan, Richard Willet,</hi> Eſquires. <hi>Samuel Gibbons, Francis Tuke,</hi> Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, <hi>Iames White</hi> of <hi>Moyglaire,</hi> Eſquire.</p>
            </div>
            <pb n="31" facs="tcp:107354:21"/>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Monaghan.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Honourable Maſter Iuſtice <hi>Coote,</hi> the High Sheriff for the time being, <hi>William Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton, Henry Teniſon, Robert Ecklin, Charles Deer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Hugh Montgomery, John Uſher, James Curry, James Moore Arthur Brownlow, James Tiſdall, Edward Davys, Richard Johnſton, Francis Lucas,</hi> Senior, <hi>Francis Lucas,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Bryan Norbury, William Wyſhart, Blayney Owens, Henry Richard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, John Corry George Buchannon, Alexander Montgomery, Richard Pockrich, Gilbert Eccles, Richard Liegh, Joſeph Johnſton, Timothy Armi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage, Walter Dawſon Thomas Wildman,</hi> and <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Chappell,</hi> Eſquires; Captain <hi>Francis Butler,</hi> Captain <hi>Robert Stephenſon,</hi> Captain <hi>Hans Stephen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, John Leſlie,</hi> Dean of <hi>Dromore, John Smith,</hi> Arch-Deacon of <hi>Clogher, William Smith, John Lawe, John Foſter, Ralph Barloe, John Knox, Andrew Montgomery,</hi> and <hi>William Pockrick,</hi> Clerks, the Provoſt of <hi>Monaghan,</hi> for the time being, <hi>Charles Congreve, Robert Maxwell, John</hi> Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, <hi>Francis Roſe, Benjamin Roſe, Dudley Teni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, Henry Evet, John Forſter, James Stanees, Richard Allen, John Graham, Richard Fitch, Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cis Dobb, William Johnſton, David Jones, Thomas Jones,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the <hi>Queens County.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The High Sheriff for the time being, The Honourable <hi>Robert Fitz-Gerald,</hi> Eſquire, Sir <hi>John Mead,</hi> Knight, Sir <hi>Edward Maſſey,</hi> Knight, <hi>John VVeaver,</hi> Senior, <hi>John VVeaver,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Robert Warneford, Walter Weldon, Thomas Pigott,
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:107354:22"/>St. Leger Gilbert, George Waburton, Richard VVar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burton</hi> Senior, <hi>Richard Warburton,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Hartpole, Thomas Carr, Gilbert Rawſon, Richard Hanſard, John Spranger, John Barrington, Periam Pole, Richard Priar, Dudly Cosby</hi> Eſquires. <hi>Andrew Nisbitt,</hi> Clerk, <hi>Abraham May, Lancelott Sands, John Stringer,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>Richard Seager, Denny Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>champe, Thomas Ueaſey, Phillip Wheeler, Went<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>worth Harman,</hi> Eſquires; Doctor <hi>Charles Crow, Robert Piggot,</hi> of <hi>Cappard, William Brereton, George Mervin, Stephen Fitz-Gerald, Oliver, Welſh, Edward Stubbers,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>William Gray, Thomas Starkey, William Deſpard, Stanley, Starkey Roger Allen, Dennis Dugan, Joſaph Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tridge, Hopton Harris, Samuel Whitſhedd,</hi> Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen, <hi>Maurice Kannely,</hi> and <hi>Richard Hall,</hi> Clerks, <hi>Robert Finn, Lemuell Wagſtaffe, William Rig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way, James Wall, John Short,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>Nicholas Carleton, William Newſtead,</hi> Eſquires.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Roſcomon.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Robert Kinge,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>George St. George,</hi> Baronet, Sir <hi>Edward Crofton,</hi> Baronet, <hi>John King, VVilliam Caulfield</hi> Eſquires, Sir <hi>Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thur Cole,</hi> Baronet, <hi>Henry Sandford,</hi> Eſquire, Maſter Serjeant <hi>Neave, Arthur St. George, VVilliam Handcock, Gilbert King, Henry St. George, Andrew Blackburne, John Dogherty, John French, John Mahon, Robert Sandys,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>George Digby,</hi> Clerk, <hi>Edward Madden, John Reynolds Theophi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lus Jones</hi> Eſquires; Maſter <hi>Gilbert Gardiner, Toby Molloy, Gilbert Ormsby, Edward Ormsby, Gil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Donellan, George Crofton, Henry Dodwell,</hi> Eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quires; Maſter <hi>Bryan Cummin,</hi> Maſter <hi>Thomas Walker,</hi> Maſter <hi>Alexander Erwin,</hi> Maſter <hi>Henry
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:107354:22"/>Erwin,</hi> Maſter <hi>Humberſton VVeſtby<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> Maſter <hi>Lewis Hawks,</hi> Collonel <hi>Daniel Hudſon,</hi> Maſter <hi>Robert Goldſmith,</hi> Maſter <hi>Dennis Delany,</hi> Maſter <hi>Edward Kelly,</hi> Maſter <hi>Dean Cope,</hi> Maſter <hi>Thomas Headen,</hi> Maſter <hi>Jeremiah Law,</hi> Clerk, Maſter <hi>John Drury,</hi> Maſter <hi>Edward Drury,</hi> the Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raigns of <hi>Athlone, Roſcomon</hi> and <hi>Tulske,</hi> for the time being; the Burgomaſter of <hi>Boyle</hi> for the time being.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Sligoe.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>Robert King,</hi> Baronet, <hi>Edward Wingfield, Hugh Morgan, John Kinge, Piercy Gethin, Roger Smith, Arthur Cooper, William Griffith, Mathew Ormsby, Jeremiah Jones, Lewis Jones, Adam Orms<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by, William Ormsby, George Wood, Charles Hara, Benjamin Burton, Keane Hara, Thomas Griffith, Robert Follyott, Chriſtopher Jones,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqs</abbr> 
                  <hi>William Smith, Philip Cox, James Barrett, Stephen Orms<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by, William Fibbs, James Devitt,</hi> Gentlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County Palatine of <hi>Tipperary.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>Sir <hi>John Meade,</hi> Knight, Lord Viſcount <hi>Ikeryne, Thomas Sadler, James Harriſon, John Ottway, John Bayly,</hi> Eſquires; Sir <hi>Thomas Oſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burne,</hi> Knight, <hi>Charles Allcock, Stephen Moore, Thomas Moore, Richard Moore, Samuel Greene, Iohn Buckworth, Robert Blenerhaſſit, Thomas Carter, Iohn Perry, William Vaughan,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Robert Bredon, Patrick Hackett,</hi> Clerks; <hi>William Armeſtrong, John Pike, Symon Broadſtreet, Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Stopford, Anthony Cheamley, Iohn Cooke, Oliver Latham, Kingſmell Pennefather,</hi> Eſquires. <hi>Andrew Roe, Iohn Cooley,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>William
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:107354:23"/>Jarvin, Thomas Cleare,</hi> Senior, <hi>Iames Dawſon,</hi> Eſquires. The High-Sheriff for the time being; the Mayor of <hi>Caſhell</hi> for the time being; the Mayor of <hi>Clonmell</hi> for the time being; the So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veraign of <hi>Fethard</hi> for the time being. <hi>David Low</hi> and <hi>William Lane, George Burdett, Charles Laug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ley, John Hunt, Phan. Cooke,</hi> Iunior, Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men. <hi>George Read,</hi> Eſquire. <hi>Thomas Salmon, William Latham, Charles Robinſon, Joſeph Tud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kins, Michael Stanley,</hi> Gentlemen. <hi>Admundiſham Cuffe,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> 
                  <hi>Philip Carleton,</hi> Gent. <hi>Humphry Min<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chin, Hector Vaughan,</hi> Eſquires. <hi>John Minchin</hi> of <hi>Annagh, John Minchin</hi> of <hi>Shangarry,</hi> Gentlemen. <hi>Thomas Batty, John White</hi> of <hi>Abbey, John White</hi> of <hi>Ardfinane, Philip Carleton</hi> of <hi>Clonmell, Richard Denniſon</hi> of the ſame, <hi>Richard Newport</hi> of the Abby, <hi>Robert Boreman</hi> of <hi>Nenagh,</hi> Gentlemen; <hi>Richard Whaley, Joſeph Lloyd, Robert Cole</hi> of <hi>Bal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lymach,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Robert Minute</hi> of Gentleman; <hi>Daniel Gahan,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Joſeph Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, Anthony Carrol, William Worth, Richard Walter, Nicholas Southcoate,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>William Minchin, Iſaac Hales,</hi> and <hi>Richard Baker,</hi> Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Tyrone.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The High-Sheriff for the time being, <hi>Henry Mervin</hi> and <hi>James Hamilton,</hi> Eſquires, Knights of the Shire; <hi>Thomas Knox, John Hamilton, Audley Mervin, Oliver Mc. Cauſland,</hi> Eſquires: Sir <hi>Robert Staples,</hi> Baronet, <hi>Richard Johnſton,</hi> Eſquire, Sir <hi>Thomas Packenham,</hi> Knight, and <hi>David Creighton,</hi> Eſquire, Burgeſſes of the ſaid County, Collonel <hi>Theobald Cawlfield,</hi> Collonel <hi>John Cawlfield,</hi> Sir <hi>Triſtram Beresford,</hi> Baronet,
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:107354:23"/>
                  <hi>Hugh Hamell, James Moore,</hi> of <hi>Anacloy, Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chibald Robinſon, James Murray, Patrick Hamil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton, William Stewart,</hi> of <hi>Killymoon George Buch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>annan, Thomas Morris, John Leſlie, William Hamil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> of <hi>Mayagh, William Latham, Charles Eccles, John Houſton, Andrew Stewart,</hi> of <hi>Irey, James Moore,</hi> of <hi>Deſertereagh, George Stewart, Francis Nevill,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Thomas Edwards, David Mac Clenaghan,</hi> of <hi>Strabane, William Maxwell,</hi> of the ſame <hi>William Hamilton,</hi> of <hi>Mountalony, James Hamilton,</hi> of <hi>Tilidony, William Cairns, Allen Moore, William Moore, Stewart Blacker, Robert Lowry, Charles Young, John Dowglaſſe, Thomas Cooper, William Goodlett,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>Warham Jemmett, Nicholas Carleton, John Latham</hi> Eſquires.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the City of <hi>Waterford.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Mayor and Sheriffs for the time being; <hi>Anthony Suxbury,</hi> Eſquire; Recorder, <hi>Richard Chriſtmaſſe John Maſon, Joſeph Ivie, John Hal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lam,</hi> and <hi>John Head,</hi> Eſquires; Alderman, <hi>VVil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Dennis,</hi> Alderman, <hi>Abraham Smith,</hi> Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, <hi>Benjamin Boſton,</hi> Maſter <hi>Samuel Frith,</hi> Merchant.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Waterford.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The High Sheriff for the time being, Sir <hi>Thomas Osburne,</hi> Knight, The Honourable <hi>Henry Petty, John Maſon,</hi> Eſquire, <hi>John Dalton,</hi> Clerk, Dean of <hi>VVaterford, Richard Chriſtmaſſe, James Mutlow, VVilliam Dobbin, Henry Nichell,</hi> and <hi>John Otherington,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Eccles,</hi> Clerk, Arch Dean of <hi>Liſmore, William Bucknore, Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward May, Joſeph Ivie, Timothy VVall, Robert
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:107354:24"/>Carew, John Nettles, Roger Power, VVilliam Great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racks, Andrew Bagg, William Browning, William Congreue, Edward Hibbert,</hi> and <hi>Thomas Croker,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Beverly Uſher, Samuel Frith, Edward Cranwell, Ralph Greene, Michael Carew,</hi> and <hi>Richard Bagg,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>Simon Ratcliffe,</hi> Clerk, <hi>Francis Beecher,</hi> Clerk.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Weſtmeath.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Robert Rochfort,</hi> Eſquire; His Majeſty's At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney General, and Speaker to the Honourable Houſe of Commons, <hi>Oliver Lambert,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſq</abbr> Sir <hi>Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Packenham,</hi> Knight, <hi>George Peyton, William Handcock, Charles Lambert,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqrs</abbr> Sir <hi>John Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gerſon,</hi> Knight, <hi>Walter Pollard, Thomas Smith, Tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas Handcock, John Cooke, James Nugent, Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Packenham, Henry Dodwell, Henry St. George, John Wood,</hi> Iunior, <hi>John Adams Barachias Low, Richard Pilkington, Lewis Meares,</hi> Senior, <hi>Lewis Meares,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Edward Bertles Alexander Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, John Percivall, Chriſtopher Nugent,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Arthur Judge</hi> Gentleman, <hi>Henry Humphreys,</hi> Eſquire, <hi>Thomas Magan, Edmond Branchwaite, James Pollard,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>Robert Smith'</hi> Clerk <hi>Thomas Smith,</hi> of <hi>Killtoome, William Chapman,</hi> Gentlemen, <hi>Hugh Bowen, Caleb Gay, William Gay,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Robert Temple,</hi> Gentleman, <hi>Mungo Campbell,</hi> Eſquire; <hi>Dominick French,</hi> Gentleman, <hi>John Darby,</hi> Eſquire.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>Wexford.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>The Right Honourable <hi>Phillip Savage, Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thew Forde, Daniel Wibrants, John Harvey, Francis Anneſley, Thomas Crawford, John Seymoure, Richard Barry,</hi> Eſquires; Sir <hi>Richard Bulckley,</hi> Sir <hi>Ni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cholas
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:107354:24"/>Loftus, John Chicheſter, Abell Ram,</hi> 
                  <abbr>Eſqrs</abbr> 
                  <hi>Robert Woleſley, Anderſon Saunders, John Cliffe, Nathaniel Boyſe, Maurice Anneſley Henry Loftus, Cadwallider Edwards, John VVintworth, Thomas Dulter, Thomas Milling, Joſhua Tench, Anthony Cliffe, Samuel Tench, Henry Jeford, Charles Buggs, Andrew Ram, William Cole, Roger Lindon, Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Anſlow, James Stopford, Jeremy Simms, Ed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Rogers, Lawrence Davys, John Grogan, James White, Henry Archer, John Shapland, Thomas Ivory, Thomas Phillipps, VVilliam Hore,</hi> Soveraign of <hi>Roſſe,</hi> for the time being, Mayor of <hi>VVexford,</hi> for the time being, Soveraign of <hi>Newborrough, <hi>alias</hi> Gory, Richard Nixon, Henry Hutton, John Smith, John VVhite, Heygate Boyd John Bunburry, Nathaniel Stephens, John Napper, John Fenn, Samuel Pitt, Henry Napper, Simon Younge, John Grogan</hi> Portreeve <hi>Eniſcorthy,</hi> for the time being.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>For the County of <hi>VVicklow.</hi>
               </head>
               <p>
                  <hi>John Price, Richard Edwards,</hi> Eſquires, Sir <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Buckley,</hi> Baronet, <hi>Willam Hoey,</hi> Eſquire, Senior, <hi>William Mathews, Thomas Keightly, VVil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Robinſon, Chriſtopher Carlton, Robert Strat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford, Richard Thompſon, Evan Price, Owen Jones, Thomas Burrows, Chriſtopher Collwell, William Fownes, Tichburne VVeſt, Peter Craddock, Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Hoey,</hi> Iunior, <hi>Abram Nickſon, Thomas Phil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lipps, Charles Ferrers, John Hackett,</hi> Eſquires, <hi>Talbott Keane,</hi> Gentleman, <hi>Anthony Archer, Robert Graydon,</hi> and <hi>Richard Gardiner</hi> Eſquires.</p>
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:107354:25"/>
               <p>And the ſaid Commiſſioners, in Order to a ſpeedy Execution of this Act, ſhall, and are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Required in their reſpective Counties, Cities, Buroughs, Towns, Baronies and Places, to meet together at the moſt uſual, and common place of Meeting, within ſuch of the ſaid Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Cities, Buroughs, Towns, Baronies and Places, reſpectively, on the Ninth Day of <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cember,</hi> in the Year of our Lord, One thouſand Six hundred Ninety ſeaven; and the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or ſo many of them as ſhall be preſent at the Firſt General Meeting, or the major part of them, may by their Conſents and Agreements, devide as well themſelves as other the Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners not then preſent for the Execution of this Act, into Baronies, Hundreds, Wards, Towns, Villages, and other places within their Limits, Priviledged or Vnpriviledged, in ſuch Manner and Form, as to them ſhall ſeem Expedient; and ſhall Direct their ſeveral, or joint Precept, or Precepts, to ſuch Inhabitants, High-Conſtables, Petty-Conſtables, Bailiffs, and other ſuch the Officers and Miniſters, and ſuch Number of them, as they in their Diſcretion ſhall think moſt convenient to be Preſentors and Aſſeſſors, requi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring them to appear before the ſaid Commiſſioners at ſuch time and place, as they ſhall appoint, not exceeding Eight days, and at ſuch their appea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring, the Commiſſioners, or ſo many of them as ſhall be thereunto Appointed, ſhall openly Read, or cauſe to be Read unto them, the Rates in this Act mentioned, and openly Declare the Effect of their Charge unto them, and how, and in what manner they ought, and ſhould make their Certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficates according to the Rates aforeſaid; and then, and there, prefix another day to the ſaid
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:107354:25"/>Perſons to appear before the ſaid Commiſſioners, and bring in their Certificates of the Names, and Sir-names, Qualities, Degrees, Titles, Eſtates, Profeſſions, Imployments and Trades, of all and every the Perſons Dwelling, or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiding within the Limits of thoſe places, with which they ſhall be Charged, and of all other things in Reſpect whereof any Perſon is, or may be Chargeable by this Act; together with the Aſſeſſments of the Reſpective Rates hereby Impoſed on each particular Perſon, according to the Rules and Directions hereof, without Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cealment, Love, Favour, Dread, or Malice, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on pain of Forfeiture of any Summ not exceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Five Pounds, to be Levied as by this Act is Appointed; and ſhall alſo then Return the Names of Two or more able, and ſufficient Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons within the Bounds and Limits of thoſe Pariſhes or Places, where they ſhall be Appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Reſpectively, as aforeſaid, to be Collectors of the Money due to His Majeſty by this Act, for whoſe Collecting and Paying unto the Receiver, or Receivers, to be Appointed by the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners for the Reſpective Baronies in manner following: Such Money as they ſhall be Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged withal, the Pariſh or Place by whom they ſhall be Imployed, ſhall be Anſwerable; which Certificate and Aſſeſſments, ſhall be Aſſertained, and Returned unto the Commiſſioners, at, or before the Tenth Day of <hi>January,</hi> in the Year of Our Lord, One thouſand Six hundred Nine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſeaven, and upon the Delivery, or Returning in of ſuch Certificates, or Aſſeſſments, unto the ſaid Commiſſioners, they or any Two or more of them, ſhall forthwith Iſſue out, and Deliver their Warrants of Eſtreats to ſuch Collectors,
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:107354:26"/>as aforeſaid, for the ſpeedy Collecting and Levy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the ſaid Aſſeſſments, and all Moneys and Rates due thereupon, according to the Intent and Directions of this Act, of which the ſaid Collectors are hereby Required to make Demand of the Parties themſelves, or at the places of their laſt Abode, within Six days after the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt of ſuch Warrants or Eſtrates; and to Levy and Pay in at ſuch place, as the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners ſhall appoint unto the reſpective Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rony Collector or Receiver, and the reſpective Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceivers are hereby Impowered and Required to call upon, and haſten the Collectors to the ſaid Payments; and in Default thereof, to Levy by Warrant under the Hands and Seals of any Two or more of the Commiſſioners, upon the reſpective Collectors by Diſtreſs, ſuch Summ and Summs of Money as they have Received, and as ought to have by them been paid, and are not paid, by Reaſon of their Failure in do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing their Duty reſpectively, according to the Direction of this Act.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That a true Duplicate of the whole Summ charged within every Barony, Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred, Pariſh, Ward, Village and place, Rated and Aſſeſſed purſuant to this Act, without naming the perſons, ſhall under the Hands and Seals of two or more of the Commiſſioners thereunto appointed, be returned into His Majeſties Court of Exchequer, before the Eight and Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth Day of <hi>February,</hi> One thouſand Six hundred Ninety ſeaven all Appeals being firſt determin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; and in like manner within Thirty days after each of the days of the ſaid Quarterly Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments; and the like Duplicates be alſo in con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:107354:26"/>time made out and delivered unto the Receiver-General, ſo as every of them may be duly Charged to anſwer their reſpective Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lections and Receipts: And that the ſaid ſeveral ſumms be paid in each County, to ſuch perſon or perſons as ſhall be appointed by the Chief Governour, or Governours of this Kingdom, for the time being, to that Purpoſe, Purſuant to this Act, of which Appointment notice is to be given in Ten Days before the payment thereof by Publick Proclamation, to be Iſſued by ſuch Chief Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour or Governours, and that the payment of ſuch ſumms in each County, to ſuch perſon or perſons ſo to be appointed, and the Receipt under the Hands of ſuch perſon or perſons ſo Authorized by ſuch Chief Governour, or Governours, own<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Receipt of ſuch ſumm, ſhall be a ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient Diſcharge to the County, or place from which the ſame is Received; and as ſufficient as any Exchequer Acquittance: And upon return of any ſuch Certificate or Aſſeſſment, the ſaid Commiſſioners, or any two or more of them, ſhall, and may (if they ſee cauſe) Examine the Preſenters thereof; and if the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, or any two or more of them within their ſeveral Limits, ſhall at the time of the Delivery of the ſaid Certificates, or within Twelve days after, have knowledge, or reaſonable cauſe of ſuſpition, that any perſon or perſons who ought to be mentioned in the ſaid Certificate, is, or are omitted, or that any perſon or perſons in the ſaid Certificates mentioned, is not, or are not fully and duly Charged according to the true intent of this Act, the ſaid Commiſſioners, or any two or more of them, ſhall have Power to warn ſuch perſon or perſons to appear be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:107354:27"/>them at a day and place prefixed to be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amined touching the premiſſes or any matter which may any-wife concern the ſame; and if the perſon or perſons warned to be examined, ſhall neglect to appear, not having a reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Excuſe for ſuch his Default, every perſon ſo making Default, ſhall pay unto His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty double the Summ or Rate he ſhould, or ought to have beén ſet at. And moreover, the ſaid Commiſſioners, or any two or more of them, ſhall have Power by any Lawful ways and Means, to Examine and Enquire into all mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters and things for, or by Reaſon of which any perſons are Chargeable by this Act, and to ſet ſuch Rate or Rates upon ſuch perſons, as ſhall be according to the true intent and meaning of this Act. That the Collectors for each Pariſh, ſhall have Six pence in the Pound for what Money, they ſhall pay to the Receiver of each Barony<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> or Hundred; and that the Receiver, or Receivers for each Barony, or Hundred, ſhall have Four pence in the Pound for what Money he or they ſhall pay to the Perſon or perſons to be appointed by the Chief Governour, or Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernours, of this Kingdom, for the time being, as aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority foreſaid, That the Preſenters and Aſſeſſors for each Pariſh within this Kingdom, for their La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour and Pains, and performing their reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Duties in the due execution of this Act, ſhall have, and receive Six pence for every Twenty ſhillings <hi>Sterling,</hi> they ſhall Aſſeſs, and which ſhall be received by the Receiver, or Receivers of each Barony, for which ſuch Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſors, or Preſenters ſhall be reſpectively ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:107354:27"/>as ſuch in purſuance of this Act; to be paid by the ſeveral and reſpective Receivers of the ſeveral Baronies: Which ſaid payment of Six pence <hi>per</hi> pound, as aforeſaid, ſhall by the Receiver, or Receivers of the Barony, or County, be allowed unto ſuch Collectors, reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctively, as good payment for ſo much; and the ſaid Collectors reſpectively, are hereby diſcharged from any Claim of His Majeſty touching the ſaid Summ of Six pence, <hi>per</hi> pound. And to the end the ſaid Aſſeſſors, or Preſenters may have the more regard to the due execution of their Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, as Aſſeſſors, or Preſenters, according to the true intent and meaning of this preſent Act.</p>
               <p>Be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the Commiſſioners before-named for the execution of this Act, or any Two of them, ſhall, and are hereby Impowered and Required to Adminiſter an Oath, to the reſpective Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſors or Preſenters of the ſeveral Pariſhes, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectively appointed them to Aſſeſs in purſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of this Act, <hi>That they will according to the beſt of their underſtanding, truly perform the Office of Aſſeſſors, or Preſenters, to them reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctively committed, without Concealment, Love, Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour, Partiality, Expectation of Reward, Dread, Ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred, or Malice, according to the true intent and mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of this Act,</hi> And the ſaid Aſſeſſors, or Preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers are hereby Required before they enter into, or upon the execution of their Office, to take the ſaid Oath accordingly. And for the careful Writing and Tranſcribing the ſaid Warrants, Eſtreats and Duplicates in due time, and for making Certificates upon Appeals.</p>
               <pb n="44" facs="tcp:107354:28"/>
               <p>Be it further Enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, That the Commiſſioners Clerks who ſhall reſpectively perform the ſame, ſhall by Warrant under three or more of the Commiſſioners Hands, have and receive from the reſpective Perſon or Perſons who ſhall be appointed in each Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, by the Chief Governour, or Governours of this Kingdom, for the time being, as aforeſaid, to Receive the ſeveral Summs purſuant to this Act, three Pence in the pound, of all ſuch Monies as they ſhall have received by Vertue of ſuch Warrants and Eſtreats, who are hereby ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to pay the ſame accordingly.</p>
               <p>And if any Perſon or Perſons ſhall refuſe to pay the ſeveral Summ and Summs, and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portions appointed by this Act, for ſuch Perſons to pay, within the ſpace of Ten Days after Demand, or Notice left at the place of Reſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence, or Dwelling of ſuch Perſons, by the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficer or Collector of the place, according to the Precepts, or Eſtreats, to him Delivered by the ſaid Commiſſioners; it ſhall be Lawful to, and for ſuch Officer, or Collector, who is hereby there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto Authorized and Required for Non-payment thereof to Diſtrain the Goods or Chattles of ſuch Perſon or Perſons, and the Diſtreſs ſo taken, to keép by the ſpace of Eight days, at the Coſts and Charges of the Owners thereof; and if the ſaid Owner doth not pay the Summ of Money Due by this Act, within the ſaid Eight days, then the ſaid Diſtreſs to be Apprai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>y Two or mo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e of the Inhabitants, where the ſaid Diſtreſs <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s Taken, and the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e to be Sold by the ſaid Officer, for payment of the ſaid Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, and the Over-plus coming by the ſaid Sale (if any be) over and above the Charges of Tak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:107354:29"/>and Keéping the ſaid Diſtreſs to be imme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diately reſtored to the Owner thereof; And if any Perſon or Perſons Aſſeſſed by this Act, ſhall Refuſe, or Neglect to pay the ſumm or ſumms ſo Aſſeſſed, by the ſpace of Ten Days after Demand, as aforeſaid, where no ſufficient Diſtreſs can, or may be found, whereby the ſame may be Levyed; in every ſuch Caſe, Threé of the Commiſſiones by this Act appointed, for any ſuch City, County, or place, are hereby Authorized by Warrants under their Hands and Seals, to commit ſuch perſon or perſons to the Common Goal, there to be kept without Bail or Mainprize, untill payment ſhall be made. And if any Perſon certified Aſſeſſed, or Rated, find him, or herſelf agrieved with ſuch Aſſeſſing, or Rating, and do within Five Days after De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand thereof, make Complaint to the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, they, or any Threé or more of them, (whereof two ſhall be of the Commiſſioners who Signed, or Allowed, his, or her Rate) ſhall, and may within Seaven Days next after ſuch Complaint, particularly Examine the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſo Complaining, upon his, or her Oath, touching the ſame; and upon due Examination, or Knowledge thereof, Abate, Defaulk, Encreaſe, or Inlarge the ſaid Aſſeſſments; and the ſame ſo Abated, Encreaſed, or Enlarged, ſhall be Eſtreated by them into the Exchequer, in manner aforeſaid. And to that end, the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners are hereby Required to Meét together, for the Determining ſuch Complaints, and Appeals accordingly.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That every Perſon to be Rated by this Act, ſhall be Rated at ſuch place where he,
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:107354:30"/>or ſhe, with his, or her Family ſhall be Reſident, at the time of the Execution of this Act. And that every perſon not being a Houſholder, nor having a certain place for Abode; and all Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants ſhall be Taxed at the place where they are Reſident at the time of the Execution of this Act. The Tax upon ſuch Servants to be paid by their reſpective Maſters or Miſtreſſes, and to be Deducted out of their Wages; which De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duction the ſaid Maſter or Miſtreſs, is hereby Impowered to make.</p>
               <p>Provided always, That if any perſon having ſeveral Manſion-Houſes, or places of Reſidence, ſhall be double Charged, by Vertue of this Act, that upon Certificate made by Two or more of the Commiſſioners for the County, City, or Place, which Certificate, the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners are hereby Required to give without Delay, Feé, or Reward, of his, or her Perſonal Reſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence, under their Hands and Seals, of the Summ or Summs there charged, upon him, or them, or in what Capacity, or Reſpect, he or they were ſo Charged, and upon Oath made of ſuch Certificate, before any Iuſtice of the Peace of the County, or place where ſuch Certificate ſhall be made; which Oath the ſaid Iuſtice of the Peace is hereby Authorized to Adminiſter; then the Perſon or Perſons ſo doubly Charged, ſhall for ſo much as ſhall be certified, be Diſcharged in every other County, City or Place. And if any Perſon at the time of the Aſſeſſing, ſhall be out of the Realm, ſuch perſon ſhall be Rated where ſuch perſon was laſt abiding within the Realm; And if any perſon that ought to be Taxed by Vertue of this Act, by changing his place of Reſidence, or by Fraud, or Covin, ſhall Eſcape from the Taxa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion,
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:107354:30"/>and not be Taxed, and the ſame be pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved before the Commiſſioners, or any Two of them, or two Iuſtices of the Peace of the County where ſuch perſon Dwelleth, or Reſideth, at any time within Twelve Months next enſuing af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter ſuch Taxation made; every perſon that ſhall ſo Eſcape from the ſaid Taxation, and Payment, ſhall be Charged upon proof thereof, at the double Value of ſo much as he ſhould, or ought to have beén Taxed by this Act, the ſaid double Value upon Certificate thereof made into the Exchequer, by the Commiſſioners, or Iu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices, before whom ſuch proof ſhall be made, to be Levyed of the Goods, Chattles, Lands and Tenements of ſuch perſons, towards the Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>Provided always, That the Commiſſioners within any County, or place within their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Limits, or the major part of them, ſhall Tax, and Aſſeſs every other Commiſſioner joyned with them: And the Commiſſioners within their Diviſion, ſhall Aſſeſs every Aſſeſſor within their Diviſion; and as well all Summs upon every of the ſaid Commiſſioners and Aſſeſſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors, as the Aſſeſſments Made and Preſented by the Preſenters, as aforeſaid, ſhall be Written, Eſtreated, Levyed, and Gathered, as the ſame ſhould, and ought to have beén, if the ſaid Commiſſioners had not beén Named Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That if any Aſſeſſor, Collector, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver, or any other Perſon appointed by the Commiſſioners, ſhall wilfully neglect, or refuſe to perform his Duty in the due and ſpeédy Execution of this preſent Act, the ſaid reſpective
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:107354:31"/>Commiſſioners, or any two or more of them, may, and ſhall by vertue of this Act, have Power and Authority to commit ſuch Aſſeſſor, Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lector, or Receiver to Goal, till he or they have done his, or their Duty according to this Act; or to impoſe on ſuch perſon or perſons ſo re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſing or neglecting their Duties, any Fine not exceéding Twenty pounds for any one Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence, at their Diſcretion; the ſame to be Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vyed and Certified as aforeſaid, into His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty's Court of Exchequer, and Charged upon the reſpective Receivers amongſt the reſt of the rates aforeſaid. And the ſaid Commiſſioners, or any two or more of them, may, or ſhall from time to time call for, and require an Account from the reſpective Receivers, of all the Monies received by them, of the ſaid Collectors, and of the payment thereof, according to the direction of this Act; and in caſe of any failure in the premiſſes, the ſaid Commiſſioners, or any two or more of them, are hereby required to cauſe the ſame to be forthwith Levyed and paid ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the true intent and meaning of this Act: And in caſe of any Controverſy ariſing between the ſaid Commiſſioners, concerning the ſaid Rates or Aſſeſſments, the Commiſſioners that ſhall be concerned therein, ſhall have no Voice, but ſhall withdraw during the Debate of ſuch Controverſy, until it be determined by the reſt of the Commiſſioners; and in default thereof, that the Commiſſioners then preſent, ſhall have power, and are hereby required to impoſe ſuch Fine or Fines, as to them ſhall be thought fit, upon ſuch Commiſſioners ſo re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſing to withdraw, not exceéding Twenty pounds, and to cauſe the ſame to be Levyed
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:107354:31"/>and Paid, as other Fines to be impoſed by ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of this Act, are to be Levyed and Paid; and all Queſtions and Differences that ſhall ariſe touching any of the ſaid Rates, Taxes, Aſſeſſments, or Levies, and the Collecting there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of ſhall be heard and finally determined by Threé or more of the Commiſſioners, upon Complaint thereof to them made by any perſon or perſons thereby grieved, without further Trouble or Sute in Law: And the ſaid Receiver-Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral, his Deputy, or Deputies, ſhall give acquit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tances <hi>Gratis,</hi> to the ſaid Barony-Receivers, who ſhall likewiſe give Acquittances <hi>Gratis,</hi> to the ſaid Pariſh-Collectors, for all Monies of them reſpectively Received, in purſuance of this Act; which Acquittances, ſhall be a full Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge to ſaid Collectors reſpectively: And the ſaid Collectors ſhall make, and deliver to the ſaid Receivers-General, their Deputy, or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puties, a perfect Schedule, fairly written in Parchment, under their Hands and Seals, Signed and Allowed by any two or more of the reſpective Commiſſioners, containing the Names and Surnames and places of aboad, of every perſon within their reſpective Collection, that ſhall make default of payment of any the Summs that ſhall be Rated or Aſſeſſed on ſuch perſon by vertue of this Act; and the Summ and Summs charged on every ſuch perſon, the ſame to be returned by him into His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty's Exchequer, whereupon every ſuch perſon making default of Payment, may be charged by Proceſs of the ſaid Court according to the Courſe thereof in that behalf.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That no Letters Patents Granted by
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:107354:32"/>the King, or late Queén's Majeſties, or any of their Royal Predeceſſors, or to be Granted by His Majeſty to any perſon or perſons, Cities, Buroughs, or Towns Corporate within this Realm, or any manner of Liberties, Priviledges, or Exemptions from Subſidies, Tolls, Taxes, Aſſeſſments, or Aids, ſhall be conſtrued, or ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken to exempt any perſon or perſons, City, Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rough, or Town Corporate, or any of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants of the ſame from the Burthen or Charge of any Summ or Summs of Money Granted by this Act; and all <hi>Non-Obſtantes</hi> in ſuch Letters Patents for any ſuch purpoſe or intent, are declared to be void and of none effect.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That all Conſtables, Head-Buroughs, and other His Majeſty's Officers, ſhall, and are hereby Required and Enjoyned to be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectively Aiding and Aſſiſting in the execution of this Act, and to obey and execute ſuch Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepts, or Warrants as ſhall be to them Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected in that behalf, by the reſpective Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners hereby appointed, or to any two or more of them.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That if any Action, Plaint, Sute, or Information, ſhall be Commenced or Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecuted againſt any perſon or perſons for what he or they ſhall do in purſuance, or in Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution of this Act, ſuch perſon or perſons ſo Sued in any Court whatſoever, ſhall, or may plead the General Iſſue, not Guilty, and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on any Iſſue joyned, may give this Act, and the Special Matter in Evidence, and if the Plan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff or Proſecutor ſhall become <hi>Non</hi>-Sute, or for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bear
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:107354:32"/>further Proſecution, or ſuffer Diſcontinu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance, or if a Verdict paſs againſt him, the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant and Defendants ſhall recover Treble Coſts, for which they ſhall have the like reme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, as in caſe where Coſts by Law are given to the Defendant.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the reſpective Parents, Guar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dians and Tutors of every perſon under the age of One and twenty Years, ſhall upon De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault of payment of ſuch perſon, and upon de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand pay what is due, and payable by this Act, for every ſuch perſon Reſiding in their Family, or under their Tuition, as before herein is men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That all Money due, and payable by this Act, ſhall be paid by the particular Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors of the reſpective Counties, Cities, Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roughs, Towns, Pariſhes and places, who ſhall Collect the ſame unto the reſpective Barony Receivers, who ſhall pay the ſame unto ſuch Receiver, or Receivers as ſhall by their Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellencies the Lords Iuſtices, or other Chief Governour, for the time being, be appointed, as before is mentioned.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted, by the Authority aforeſaid, That the particular Collectors for pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of any Summs by them received unto ſuch Barony-Receiver or Receivers, ſhall not be oblidged to Travel above Twenty Miles from the place of their Habitation.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That every Receiver of any Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred, Barony, or Diviſion, from time to time
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:107354:33"/>within the ſpace of one Month next after he ſhall have received the full Summ that ſhall be Charged upon any Hundred, Barony, or Diviſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, for each particular Quarterly Payments that is to be made to ſuch Receiver, by Vertue of this Act, ſhall give the Commiſſioners who ſhall act in ſuch Hundred, Barony, or Diviſion, a Receipt under his Hand and Seal, acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledging his Receipt of the full ſumm Charged upon ſuch Hundred, Barony, or Diviſion, for ſuch particular payment; and the Receipt of ſuch Receiver, or Receivers, as ſhall be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the Lords Iuſtices of this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, or other Chief Governour or Governours of this Realm, for the time being, as aforeſaid, to every Collector of any Barony, Hundred, or Diviſion, for ſo much of the ſaid Aſſeſſments as ſhall be contained in ſuch Receipt, ſhall be a full Diſcharge to ſuch Barony, Hundred, or Divi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, againſt His Majeſty, His Heirs and Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors. And for preventing ſuch Vexations, as might be occaſioned by ſuch Perſons as ſhall be appointed to make Returns of ſuch perſon and perſons as make default of payment of the ſumm or ſumms on him, or them, Aſſeſſed by this Act. And to the intent, ſuch perſon or perſons may Return true Account or Accounts into His Majeſty's Court of Exchequer, of ſuch ſumm of Money as ſhall not be Received by them, and every of them, their, and every of their Deputy, and Deputies.</p>
               <p>Be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That if any ſuch perſon ſhall Return, or Certifie in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the ſaid Court, any Summ or Summs of Money to be in Arrear, or Vnpaid, after the ſame hath been Received; ſuch perſon or perſons
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:107354:33"/>ſo making ſuch Return or Returns, or ſhall cauſe any perſon or perſons to be Set <hi>Inſuper</hi> in the ſaid Court, for any Summ or Summs of Money that hath beén ſo Received, that then every ſuch perſon or perſons making ſuch Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turns. ſhall forfeit to every perſon or perſons that ſhall be Moleſted, Vexed or Damaged, by reaſon of ſuch unjuſt Certificate, return, or ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting <hi>Inſuper,</hi> treble Damages that ſhall be there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by occaſioned, the ſaid Damages to be recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information, in which no Eſſoin, Protection, or Wager of Law ſhall be allowed, nor any more then one Imparlance; and ſhall alſo Forfeit unto His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty, His Heirs and Succeſſors, double the Summ that ſhall be ſo unjuſtly certified or returned, or cauſed to be ſet <hi>Inſuper.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Provided always, That all Penalties and Forfeitures to be incurred for any Offences againſt this Act, for which there is no way for Levying herein before Preſcribed or Appointed, ſhall be Levyed by Warrant of any Two or more of the reſpective Commiſſioners of the Diviſion or place, where any ſuch Offence was, or ſhall be committed, by Diſtreſs, and Sale of the Goods of the Offenders, rendering the Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plus to the Owner thereof, after Deduction of reaſonable Charges for Diſtraining the ſame.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the Commiſſioners in every County, at the General Meéting to be by them appointed, after all Appeals ſhall be firſt deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined, ſhall cauſe Duplicates of the whole ſumms Charged within every Hundred, Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rony, Ward, or place, Rated and Aſſeſſed in ſuch County, in purſuance of this Act, without
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:107354:34"/>naming the perſons, to be fairly Written in Parchment, and Aſſertained under Threé or more of their Hands, reſpectively to each Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plicate; and the ſame ſo by them Subſcribed, and Aſſertained, ſhall be jointly, and together delivered to the Sheriff of ſuch County, and be by him Tranſmitted to the Exchequer, at, or before the Twenty eighth Day of <hi>February,</hi> in the Year of our Lord, One thouſand Six hundred Ninety ſeaven.</p>
               <p>Provided always, That no perſon ſhall be capable of Acting as a Commiſſioner in the Execution of this Act, before he ſhall take the Oaths, and Subſcribe the Declaration appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by this Act, <hi>(viz.)</hi>
               </p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="oath">
                  <body>
                     <p>YOU ſhall Swear, That you will duly Execute the Act, Intituled, <hi>An Act for Granting a Supply to His Majeſty, by Raiſing Money, by way of a Poll,</hi> as a Commiſſioner according to your beſt Skill and Knowledge, without Favour or Affection.</p>
                     <closer>So help you God.</closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="oath">
                  <body>
                     <p>I <hi>A. B.</hi> do Sincerely Promiſe and Swear, That I will be Faithful, and bear True Allegiance to His Majeſty King WILLIAM.</p>
                     <closer>So help me God.</closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="oath">
                  <body>
                     <p>I <hi>A. B.</hi> do Swear, That I do from my Heart, Ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hor, Deteſt, and Abjure, as Impious and Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tical, that Damnable Doctrine, and Poſition, that Princes Excommunicated, or Deprived by the Pope, or any Authority of the See of ROME, may be Depoſed or Murdered by their Subjects, or any other whatſoever. And I do Declare that no Foreign
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:107354:34"/>Prince, Perſon, Prelate, State, or Potentate, hath or ought to have any Juriſdiction, Power, Superi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ority, Preheminence, or Authority Eccleſiaſtical or Spiritual within this Realm.</p>
                     <closer>So help me God.</closer>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng" type="oath">
                  <body>
                     <p>I <hi>A. B</hi> Do Solemnly and Sincerely in the preſence of God, Profeſs, Teſtifie and Declare, that I do believe that in the Sacrament of the Lords-Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per, there is not any Tranſubſtantiation of the Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of Bread and Wine, into the Body and Blood of Chriſt, at, or after the Conſecration thereof, by any Perſon whatſoever: And that the Invocation, and Adoration of the Virgin MARY, or any other Saint, and the Sacrifice of the Maſs, as they are now Uſed in the Church of ROME, are Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perſtitious and Idolatrous. And I do Solemnly in the preſence of God, Profeſs, Teſtifie and Declare, That I do make this Declaration, and every part thereof in the Plain and Ordinary Senſe of the Words Read unto me, as they are commonly un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtood by Proteſtants, without any Evaſion, Equi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vocation, or Mental Reſervation whatſoever; and without any Diſpenſation already Granted me for this purpoſe, by the Pope, or any other Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, or Perſon whatſoever, or without Diſpenſation from any Perſon, or Authority whatſoever, or without believing that I am, or can be Acquit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted before God or Man, or Abſolved of this Decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, or any part thereof, although the Pope, or any other Perſon or Perſons, or Power whatſoever ſhould Diſpence with, or Annul the ſame, or Declare that it was Null and Void from the Beginning.</p>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
               <pb n="56" facs="tcp:107354:35"/>
               <p>Which ſaid Two laſt Oaths and Declarations, are the ſame Oaths and Declaration intended alſo to be Adminiſtred to, and be Made and Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed by ſuch (not being Quakers) as already have not taken the ſaid Oaths, and Subſcribed the ſaid Declaration, to Excuſe them from pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing double, as aforeſaid: Which Oaths and Declaration, it ſhall, and may be Lawful for any Two, or more of the Commiſſioners, to Adminiſter, and take. And they are hereby Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thorized and Required to Adminiſter, and take the ſame, to, and from any other Commiſſioner. And in Caſe any Perſon Named a Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, for putting in Execution this Act, ſhall preſume to act as a Commiſſioner before he ſhall have taken the ſaid Oaths, and Made, and Subſcribed the ſaid Declaration, he ſhall Forfeit to His Majeſty, the Summ of Two hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred pounds.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That every Houſholder ſhall upon demand of the reſpective Aſſeſſors of the ſever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Pariſhes, or Places, give an Account of the Names and Qualities of ſuch perſons as ſhall Sojourne or Lodge in their reſpective Houſes, under the Penalty of forfeiting to His Majeſty the Summ of Ten pounds to be Levyed and Recovered in ſuch manner as other Penalties in this Act mentioned, are to be Levyed and Recovered.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted, and Declared that wherever any perſon or perſons ſhall, or may be liable to be Taxed by vertue of this Act, in two or more Qualifications or Capacities, and ſhall alſo be ſo Taxed, that ſuch perſon ſhall only pay in one of the ſaid Capacities, or Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lifications,
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:107354:35"/>that is in ſuch Capacity, or Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lification, which is moſt Beneficial for His Majeſty.</p>
               <p>And be it further Enacted. That where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as there are ſeveral Summs of Money due to the People of this Kingdom, for Debts Stated and unſtated, due by the Army for Quarters, before the Four and Twentieth of <hi>June,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Nine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Two, that whatſoever Summ or Summs of Money ſhall be raiſed, Levyed or Collected by vertue of this Act, over and above One Hundred Thouſand Pounds, <hi>Sterling,</hi> pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able in the firſt place unto His Majeſty, ſhall and may be Paid and applied towards the Diſcharge of the ſaid Country Debts, Stated and Vnſtated, in juſt and equal proportions, as the ſeveral Debts ſo due bear propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to the whole of the ſaid Debts.</p>
               <p>Provided alwaies, and be it further En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted That no Foreign Proteſtant Refugee, nor any perſon who ſerved as a Private Soldier in <hi>London-derry,</hi> or <hi>Eneskillen,</hi> during the late Seige of <hi>London-derry,</hi> and all Common Sol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diers in His Majeſty's Army, and Seamen in His Majeſty's Fleét, all Matroſſes in the Train of Artillery, and all Proteſtants who ſhall come into this Kingdom after the Sixth Day of <hi>November,</hi> One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Seaven, who have not now any Eſtate, or Intereſt in this Kingdom, ſhall be wholy exempt from paying any Summ whatſoever towards this preſent Poll.</p>
               <p>And for as much great Abuſes have former<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly beén Committed to the prejudice of His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty in the execution of the former Poll Act,
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:107354:36"/>under pretence of appealing againſt Aſſeſſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments made, which Appeals having been once heard, and the Commiſſioners not having re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lived the party. Appealing, but judging him not to be Reliveable within the intention of the ſaid Act, the ſaid parties have notwithſtanding, beén afterwards Relived by other Commiſſioners of Appeals, who have taken on them to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>examine the ſaid Appeal formerly heard and determined.</p>
               <p>Be it further Enacted, That no Appeal be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing once heard and determined, ſhall be re-heard or Re-examined, nor any new Appeal be received for any matter, upon which, or upon any part of which the ſaid party hath formerly Lodged his Appeal, and beén heard to the ſame.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
